<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<recipes>
<recipe>
<ti>egg biryani</ti>
<in>basmati rice#3 cups</in>
<in>egg#4 boiled + 3 scrambled</in>
<in>cinnamon#2</in>
<in>clove#4</in>
<in>cardamom#3</in>
<in>bay leaf#1</in>
<in>star anise#1</in>
<in>jeera#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>oil#1 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>water</in>
<in>mint</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Hard boil 4 eggs, peel it and cut it into half lengthwise.
2. Sprinkle a pinch of biryani masala, little salt and little corn flour on the eggs and shallow fry. Keep it aside.
3. Scramble the remaining 3 eggs with little salt and black pepper powder and keep aside.
4. Cook the rice in plenty of water (about 10 cups) along with 1 tblsp oil, shahi jeera, whole garam masala, salt and some mint leaves. (You can add a pinch of turmeric powder too if you want a bright yellow colour).
5. When the rice is 3/4 th cooked, drain the water and spread it on a tray to cool.
6. Preheat oven to 350 degree F.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>khandvi</ti>
<in>gram flour#1 cup</in>
<in>yogurt#1 cup</in>
<in>water#1 cup</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/8 tsp</in>
<in>asafoetida</in>
<in>ginger paste#ginger paste blueberry size</in>
<in>green chilly#green chilly paste 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>coconut#grated</in>
<in>mustard seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>sesame seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly#dry</in>
<in>oil#2 tsp</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>cilantro#finely chopped for garnishing</in>
<pr>
1. Mix together the gram flour, ginger paste, green chilly paste, turmeric powder, asafoetida and required salt.
2. Add the yogurt and water gradually while stirring continuously to make a smooth paste.
3. Transfer this to a pan and cook the mixture for about 10 minutes stirring continuously. 
 Note : - There will be lot of splattering during the cooking process.
           - You can also cook the mixture in the microwave for 5 minutes stirring after every minute.
4. After the besan mixture is completely cooked and it becomes like a smooth paste, switch off the flame.
5. Using a spatula take some of the mixture and spread it onto a smooth ungreased surface immediately. (It can be the back of a stainless steel plate, baking tray, cookie sheet or just an aluminium foil.)
7. Let it cool for about 5 minutes.
8. In the meantime heat a pan and make a seasoning of mustard seeds,sesame seeds,  curry leaves and dry red chilly.
9. Sprinkle half of the seasoning over the mixture.
10. Cut into thin strips and roll up each strip into firm roll.
11. Arrange the rolls in a serving dish, garnish with the remaining seasoning, finely chopped cilantro and grated coconut.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>khaman dhokla</ti>
<in>gram flour#1 1/2 cup</in>
<in>sugar#3-4 tsp</in>
<in>oil#1 tsp</in>
<in>citric acid#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>baking soda#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>lemon juice#3-4 drops</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>mustard seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>sesame seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>asafoetida</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>water</in>
<in>sugar#1 tsp</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>coconut#grated</in>
<in>sev#for garnish</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Mix all the ingredients from batch I in a bowl with water enough to make a thick paste(like idli batter). 
2. Blend it well with a hand blender or with hand. 
3. Steam it for 15 minutes on high flame. 
4. Cut it into square pieces.
5. Tempering: Heat 1 tbsp oil. Add jeera(cumin), rai(mustard seeds), til(sesame seeds), hing(asafoetida) and karipatta(curry leaves). When it splutters add 1/2 cup water and 1 tsp sugar.
6. Pour this water slowly on dhokla pieces. 
7. Garnish this with fresh coriander, shredded fresh coconut and sev. Serve with green chutney
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>spicy lassi</ti>
<in>curd#1 cup</in>
<in>water#2 cupS</in>
<in>green chilly#2-3</in>
<in>ginger#1 piece</in>
<in>cilantro#2-3 stems</in>
<in>curry leaves#5-6 leaves</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Crush the green chillies, ginger and cilantro using a mortar and pestle or using the pulse mode of the mixie.
2. Beat the curd nicely using a fork and add the water to it. 
3. Mix the curd-water mixture nicely using a hand blender or with a spoon.
4. Add the crushed mixture, torn curry leaves and required salt and mix everything together.
5. Serve on a hot summer day as a refreshing drink or have with some plain rice.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>methi thepla</ti>
<in>wheat flour#2 cups</in>
<in>gram flour#2 tbsp</in>
<in>methi leaves#1/2 cup finely</in>
<in>carom seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>ginger paste#3 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly#1 tsp</in>
<in>cilantro#2 tbsp</in>
<in>curd#1/4 cup</in>
<in>baking powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>sesame seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>sugar#1 tsp</in>
<in>oil#2 tbsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Take all of the above ingredients in a large mixing bowl and mix it nicely.
2. Add required amount of warm water and knead it into a soft dough.
3. Let the dough rest for 15-20 minutes.
4. Divide the dough into lemon sized balls and roll into a circle similar to making chappttis.
5. Heat a griddle and roast the thepla just like rotis.
6. When small bubbles start appearing, flip the thepla.
7. Cook till both the sides are cooked, till you get brown spots on both the sides.
8. Transfer immediately to a hot pack to maintain its softness. Serve with curd, pickle or chutney.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>shrikhand</ti>
<in>yogurt#3 cups</in>
<in>sugar#3/4 cups</in>
<in>cardamom powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>saffron strands</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Take a clean kitchen towel or muslin cloth and put the yogurt in it.
2. Wrap the cloth and tie it. Now hang it or put it on a strainer to drain out all the water content.
3. After a few hours (min 1 hour or even overnight), you will have a thick mass of yogurt left.
           Tip :-  I usually put the tied cloth in a strainer, add some weight on top, put another vessel at the bottom and leave it in the fridge for a few hours. This way the water gets drained out without the yogurt getting sour.Another advantage is that the yogurt will remain cold and you dont have to chill the shrikhand seperately after making it.
4. Take the thick yogurt in a bowl and add the sugar to it. Whisk with a spoon till the sugar gets dissolved and it becomes creamy.
5. Now mix in the cardamom powder and the saffron milk.
6. The basic shrikhand is ready to serve. This is also called kesar shrikhand.  It is best served chilled.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>phulka</ti>
<in>wheat flour#2 cups</in>
<in>salt#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>water#3/4 cups</in>
<pr>
Method   
1. Take the chappatti flour (atta) and salt in a wide bowl.
2. Add warm water little by little while mixing everything together. Knead to form a soft dough.
3. Apply few drops of oil and knead once again. 
4. Cover it with moist kitchen towel and let it rest for atleast 15 minutes.
5. The dough become very pliable after resting. Make lemon sized balls out of the dough.   
6. Dip each ball into the dry flour and roll out into thin discs about 6-7" in diameter. 
7. In the meantime, heat a tawa/griddle on medium heat. If you are using a phulka stand, heat that too. 
8. When the griddle is hot, put the rolled out roti on it. 
9. After white spots appear, flip the roti. Wait till you have light brown spots on the other side.
10. Now remove the partially cooked roti from the tawa and place it on direct flame (using tongs). If you are not comfortable with tongs, place a phulka stand over direct flame and put the partially cooked roti on that.
11. The roti will immediately puff up like a balloon. Remove it from the heat as soon as you see brown spots.
12. Apply few drops of ghee/oil on the phulka and store it in a hot pack (or any tightly closed container) till you are ready to serve. The steam that is trapped in the hot pack will keep the rotis soft.
13. Make the rest of the phulkas in the same way.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>parwal sabzi</ti>
<in>parwal#1 lb</in>
<in>ginger paste#2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>coriander powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>cumin powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>amchoor powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil#2 tbsp</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Scrape the rough skin of the parwal and wash it. Cut each parwal lengthwise into uniform sized pieces.
2. Heat oil in a frying pan and add the ginger garlic paste. Fry for just a minute.
3. Add the sliced parwal pieces and mix together. Cover and let it cook on medium heat for about 15 minutes. 
4. Add salt and all the spice powders. Stirfry for 5-10 minutes till the parwal pieces are nicely cooked and gets a little brown colour.
5. Switch off and serve as a sidedish for rice or roti.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>palak kichadi</ti>
<in>rice#3/2 cups</in>
<in>moong dal#1 cups</in>
<in>spinach#1 bunch</in>
<in>onion#1/4</in>
<in>garlic#3</in>
<in>tomato#1</in>
<in>green chilly#2</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>goda masala#1 tsp</in>
<in>oil#1 tbsp</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Wash and soak the rice and dal for 10-15 minutes.
2. Heat oil in a pressure cooker and add the cumin seeds.
3. Next add the onion, garlic and ginger. Fry till it becomes soft.
4. Add the tomato, green chilly, goda masala, turmeric powder and fry for a minute. 
5. Next add the chopped spinach and cook till it wilts.
6. Add the rice, dal, 5 cups of water and required salt.
7. Pressure cook for 2-3 whistles or transfer to a rice cooker and cook till done.
8. Serve this warm and comforting meal with some papad and pickle.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>bisi bele bath</ti>
<in>rice#1 cups</in>
<in>toor dal#3/4 cups</in>
<in>water#5 cups</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>tomato#2</in>
<in>beans</in>
<in>drumstick</in>
<in>green peas</in>
<in>potato</in>
<in>capsicum</in>
<in>carrot</in>
<in>brinjal</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>tamarind juice#1/4 cup</in>
<in>ghee#2tbsp</in>
<in>sesame oil#tbsp</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Wash the rice and toor dal. If you have time, soak it for 10 minutes. Wash and chop the vegetables in big chunks so that it doesn't get completely mashed up.
2. Take a pressure cooker or a heavy bottomed pan and add the rice, lentils (toor dal), 1 tblsp sesame oil, onion, tomatoes and all the other vegetables.
3. Add 5 cups of water, required salt and turmeric powder. Close the cooker and pressure cook for 3-4 whistles.
4.  Alternatively if you are using a heavy bottomed pan, cook for about 45 minutes till the rice, dal and vegetables are soft. 
5. In the meantime, dry roast all the ingredients under 'Spice Mix' on low heat till everything turns light brown. Cool it and make a coarse powder. You can also add some water and make a paste.
6. After the pressure has gone down from the cooker, open the lid and turn on the heat again.
7. Mix the coarsely ground spice and the tamarind juice with the rice. 
           Tip :- If you want the rice less spicy, reduce the amount of spice powder according to your taste. Also adjust the amount of tamarind juice depending on the sourness you need. The tomatoes already adds little sourness to the dish.
8.  Heat ghee in a seperate small pan and splutter the mustard seeds. Fry the fenugreek seeds, cashews on a low heat for 30 seconds. Add the curry leaves, dry red chillies and asafoetida to this. 
9. Add this hot tempering to the bisi bele bath. Mix everything together and let it cook on low heat for about 10 minutes till all the flavours blend up. 
10. Finally add 2 tblsp of fresh ghee and switch off. Serve it piping hot with some potato chips, papad, salad or some fry. 
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>curd rice</ti>
<in>rice#1 cup</in>
<in>water#3 cups</in>
<in>milk#1.5 cups</in>
<in>curd#1.5 cups</in>
<in>cream#2 tbsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<pr>
1. Cook the rice with 3 cups of water and some salt. We need overcooked rice which gets easily mashed up.
   Tip :- If you have leftover rice, just reheat it with some additional water.
2. Once the rice is cooked, mix and mash up part of the rice.
3. Add the milk and keep mixing till all the milk gets absorbed by the rice.
4. Once you add the cold milk, the rice will cool down. If it is still hot, wait for it to become luke warm before you add the curd. This will prevent the curd from curdling.
5. Add the cream and yogurt and mix well. 
6. Heat oil for tempering in a small pan and splutter the mustard seeds.
7. Add the chana dal and urad dal and wait for it to turn reddish brown.
8. Now add the dry red chillies, curry leaves, finely chopped green chillies and finely chopped ginger. Fry for a minute. (You can add some raisins and cashews too.)
9. Add this to the curd rice. Also add the finely chooped corriander leaves and mix together.
10. Curd rice is ready to be served. You can also garnish it with more chopped cilantro or grated carrots or chopped cucumber or fresh fruits like pineapple, pomegranate, grapes, apples etc.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>rava doasi</ti>
<in>rava#1 cup</in>
<in>rice flour#1/2 cup</in>
<in>maida#2 tbsp</in>
<in>yogurt#1 cup</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1/4 cups</in>
<in>peppercorns#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly#1</in>
<in>ginger#1</in>
<in>cilantro#2</in>
<in>curry leaves#1</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Mix the rava, rice flour, maida and required salt.
2. Add finely chopped onions, green chilly, cilantro, curry leaves, grated ginger, cumin seeds and crushed peppercorns to that.
3. Add the yogurt/buttermilk and required water to make a batter thinner than normal dosa batter. Let the batter rest for 10-15 minutes.
4. Heat a non stick dosa pan on medium high heat. 
5. Take a spoon ful of batter and spread the batter from the outer side of the pan. (unlike the normal dosa which you spread from the inside out.)
6. Pour few drops of oil on top and let it cook for a couple of minutes on one side. 
7. Gently flip the dosa and cook until both the sides are golden brown.
8. Serve with coconut chutney and sambhar. You can also stuff it with masala and make rava masala dosa.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>rava idli</ti>
<in>rava#2 cups</in>
<in>green chilly#2</in>
<in>curd#2 cups</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>oil#2 tbsp</in>
<in>cilantro#3</in>
<in>curry leaves#6</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>baking soda</in>
<in>urad dal#2 tsp</in>
<in>bengal gram#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>mustard seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>cashew nuts#1 tbsp</in>
<in>ghee#2tbsp</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Roast the rava and cashews in the ghee. Mix it with sour curd and keep aside for 10-15 minutes.
2. Heat oil in a small pan, temper mustard seeds, chopped curry leaves, urad dal and bengal gram dal.
3. Once the dals are nicely cooked add the onions and green chillies and saute for 2 minutes.
4. Pour this over the rava-curd mixture.
5. Add cooking soda, salt and chopped cilantro to the above mixture and mix everything well. Add little water if the batter is too thick.
6. Grease the idli plates with few drops of oil and pour the batter.
7. Steam it for 15 minutes like idlis. Serve with spicy pudhina chutney and/or sambhar.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>upma</ti>
<in>rava#1 cup</in>
<in>mustard seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>urad dal#1 tsp</in>
<in>chana dal#1 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly#2</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>green chilly#3</in>
<in>ghee#2 tsp</in>
<in>oil#2 tsp</in>
<in>water#3/2 cups</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Roast the rava with few drops of ghee, till is the color starts changing.
2. Cut the onion into small pieces, G.chilli into halvess, and slightly grind the grated coconut(don't use water to grind).
3.In a pan put the oil, then the musturd urad and channa dhal. Fry it till it becomes slight brown color.
4. Add Red Chillies and curry leaves.
5.Then add the onion and Green Chillies and fry it till it's cooked.
6.Then to the coconut add the water and just give a slight squeeze to the coconut , so the milk comes out of it.
7. Now add this coconut and water combo to the pan and add salt as per taste.
8. Allow it to boil, then reduce the flame to simmer. Quickly add rava with constant stirring.
9. Add ghee and close the pan tightly.
10. keep the stove in simmer for around 5 to 6 minutes till all the water is absorbed and the rawa is cooked. 
11. Gently fluff up with the spoon and serve with coconut chutney or sugar. 
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>aviyal</ti>
<in>brinjal#1/4 cups</in>
<in>carrot#1/4 cups</in>
<in>green beans#1/3cups</in>
<in>drumstick#1</in>
<in>curry leaves#2</in>
<in>coconut oil#1 tbsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Cover and cook all the vegetables for 5 minutes with turmeric, salt and 1/2 cup water in a 
kadai. 
2. In the meantime grind coconut, green chilly, small onion, cumin seeds and tamarind/curd.
3. When the veggies are half cooked add the ground mixture to it and mix everything well.
4. Continue to cook on low flame till the veggies become tender. Mix everything occasionally to avoid the veggies from sticking to the bottom of the kadai.
5. The vegetables should be tender but still hold its shape. At this stage turn off the stove.
6. Drizzle some fresh coconut oil and some curry leaves on top and keep covered till you are ready to serve.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>parotta</ti>
<in>maida#2 cups</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>water#1/2 cups</in>
<in>oil#1/2 cups</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Mix the maida, salt and warm water and Knead to form dough. Cover the dough with a wet kitchen towel and let it rest for 1/2 - 1 hour.
2. Knead the dough again adding 2-3 tblsp of oil little at a time. Continue kneading the dough for 10-15 minutes till you get a soft and elastic dough. You can use the dough attachment of your grinder or a kitchen aid to make this task easier.
3. Divide the dough into small balls - 5-6 balls and leave it under the moist towel.
4. Take a dough ball and roll it out into a very thin layer as thin as possible. The dough may bounce back as you roll. Use oil for easily rolling out the dough(Do not use flour). You should be able to see the rolling surface through the stretched rolled out dough.
5. Apply a layer of oil all over the rolled out dough. Beginning with one side, fold it over and under alternatively just like making a paper fan or saree pleets.
6.Tap this folded dough on the rolling surface holding both ends with your hands. This will expand and stretch the dough lengthwise.
7. Now roll it from both ends towards the center. When it meets in the center, place one side of roll on top of the other.
8. Repeat the process for every dough ball and place it under the moist kitchen towel. In the meantime, heat a tava on medium high flame.
9. Now roll out each of the above pleeted and rolled dough and roll it again using a rolling pin.
10. Fry these on the tava with enough oil till you see brown spots on both sides.
11. Once all the parottas are done, line up the parottas one above the other. Beat it with both of your hands on the sides when it is still hot to seperate the layers.
12. Serve hot with chicken kurma, veg kurma, chalna, mutton curry, beef curry or spicy chicken curry.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>fish curry</ti>
<in>coconut#1/4 cups</in>
<in>onion#4</in>
<in>garlic#3</in>
<in>curry leaves#4</in>
<in>red chilly#3</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>fish#2</in>
<in>tomato#1</in>
<in>tamarind juice#1/4 cups</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>chilly powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>coriander powder#1 tbsp</in>
<in>curry leaves#4</in>
<in>green chilly#1</in>
<in>mustard#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>oil#2 tbsp</in>
<in>fenugreek seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>asafoetida powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>coriander leaves</in>
<pr>
Method 
1. Take a skillet and heat some oil in it. Now fry all the ingredients from batch-1.
2. Once the aroma starts coming, remove it from fire and let it cool. After it cools, grind everything together with some water to form a very fine paste and keep aside. 
3. Now take a clay pot or deep vessel, heat some oil, splutter mustard, fenugreek seeds and curry leaves. 
4. Now add the tamarind juice,chilly powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, tomatoes, salt, asafoetida powder along with the ground masala and bring it to a boil.
5. Add the fish fillets, cover and cook for 10 minutes on low-medium flame. The fish fillets are cooked when they become opaque and soft.
6. Garnish with fresh curry leaves, cilantro and split green chilly and serve hot.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>pizza</ti>
<in>maida#11/4 cups</in>
<in>water#1 cup</in>
<in>yeast#1 tbsp</in>
<in>salt#1 tsp</in>
<in>sugar#1 tsp</in>
<in>olive oil#3 tbsp</in>
<in>tomato#1</in>
<in>tomato sauce#1/2 cups</in>
<in>red chilly sauce#1 tbsp</in>
<in>garlic</in>
<in>carom seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>cheese#1 cup</in>
<pr>
Method
To make pizza dough
1. Mix the yeast with 1 cup of luke warm water and sugar and let it proof for 5 minutes. This ia to activate the yeast.
2. Take a mixing bowl, add the flour, salt and oil and mix everything together.
3. Next add the water with the activated yeast. Knead and make a dough.
4. Let the dough ball sit for 4-5 hours until it doubles in size.

To make pizza sauce
1. Mix all the ingredients under 'pizza sauce' and keep aside.
(If you use fresh tomatoes instead of canned tomato puree, blanch and peel the tomatoes, chop and cook it thoroughly. Next add the other ingredients.)

To make pizza
1. After the pizza dough doubles in volume, divide it into 2 equal parts. 
2. Take one part and roll it out using a rolling pin. You can press with fingers and roll out too.
3. The dough will be quite sticky. Use little maida to prevent sticking. Do not make the pizza base too thick as it will puff up while baking.
4. Preheat the oven  to 350 degree F and place the pizza stone inside while you get the other things done. If you do not have pizza stone, you can very well use a cookie sheet.
5. Apply few drop of olive oil on the rolled out pizza base. This is to prevent the sauce from making the base soggy.
6. Prick the base with fork at different places. This helps it to cook uniformly.
7. (Optional)At this stage you can bake the base for just 2-3 minutes.
8. Spread on some pizza sauce. Next add your choice topping. (I usually add some onions, capsicum, mushroom, pineapple pieces and shrimp).
9. Spread the cheese on top liberally.
10. Bake it in a oven preheated to 350 degrees for 10-12 minutes until the cheese melts and the pizza is done.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>pancakes</ti>
<in>maida#2 cups</in>
<in>egg#2</in>
<in>baking powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>salt#1 tsp</in>
<in>sugar#1/2 cups</in>
<in>milk#1 cups</in>
<pr>
Method
1.Beat the eggs and mix salt,sugar,baking powder.
2.Now add this to the flour and mix until there is no lumps and the batter is not too watery or too thick.
3.Now heat a nonstick pan in a medium flame and when its hot pour a spoonful of batter in the centre of the pan.
4.Add 2-3 drops of oil over the pancake.
5.Now sprinkle grated cocunut or nuts over the pancake
6. Once it turns slightly brown, flip and brown the other side too. Serve hot.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>cold coffee</ti>
<in>milk</in>
<in>sugar#2 tbsp</in>
<in>coffee powder#1 tbsp</in>
<in>vanilla ice cream#1</in>
<in>cream#1 tbsp</in>
<in>ice#4</in>
<pr>
Method:
Add all the ingredients in a shaker and shake it well. Pour it in tall glasses and serve with scoop of vanilla ice cream and grated chocolate.
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>Punjabi Kadhi</ti>
<in>Gram Flour#2 cups</in>
<in>Onion#2</in>
<in>Potato#1</in>
<in>chilly Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in>
<in>Yogurt#1 cup</in>
<in>Gram Flour#2 tbsp</in>
<in>Turmeric#1 tsp</in>
<in>Fenugreek Seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>Red Chilly#2</in><pr>1. Mix all pakora ingredients along with little water and make small pakoras of those and deep fry. Keep aside.
2. In a bowl mix yoghurt, besan, turmeric and salt and mix well. Make sure there are no lumps left behind. Add 3-4 cups of water to retain the consistency
3. Heat oil in a kadhai and add methi dana(fenugreek seeds), red chillyes and fry well. Now add the yoghurt mixture and bring it to a oil. Stir occasionally during the process. 
4. Once the kadhi starts to boil add the pakoras and bring it to a boil stirring in the process ensuring the pakoras don't break.
5. Serve punjabi kadhi with fried/roasted papad, punjabi pickle and steamed or jeera rice. </pr></recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>Lassi</ti>

<in>Yogurt#1 cup</in>
<in>Water#1 cup</in>
<in>Sugar#To Taste</in>
<in>Rose Water#1 tsp</in>
<in>Cardamom Powder#A Pinch</in><pr>Method
1. Blend together all the above ingredients together using a hand mixer or a mixie until it becomes frothy.
2. Garnish with fresh mint leaves, pistachios and serve as a cool, healthy and refreshing drink.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Dal makhani</ti>

<in>Black Urad Dal#Half Cup</in>
<in>Rajma#3 tblsp</in>
<in>Onion#3 Chopped</in>
<in>Tomato#Puree Half Cup</in>
<in>Garlic#Paste 1 TBLSP</in>
<in>Cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>Red Chilly Powder#1 tblsp</in>
<in>Cumin Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>coriander powder#2 tsp</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in>
<in>Cream#3 tblsp</in><pr>Method 
1. Soak the urad dal and rajma overnight in water.
2. Pressure cook dal and rajma until it turns soft.
3. Mash it lightly with the back of the spoon and keep aside.
4. In a pan heat oil/butter, add garlic paste and fry until it turns pink. 
5. Add cummin seeds and when they splutter add chopped onions.
6. Fry until onions turn pink. Then add tomato puree and fry until oil separates. 
7. Add red chilly powder, cummin powder, coriander powder, salt and fry well. 
8. Now add the cooked dal and rajma. 
9. Once it starts to boil, add fresh cream and let it cook on low heat for 10 minutes. 
10. Serve hot with naan/roti.</pr></recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>Channa Masala</ti>

<in>Chik peas#2 cups</in>
<in>Onion#2 small/1 large(chopped)</in>
<in>Ginger Garlic Paste#1 tblsp</in>
<in>Tomato#2 Pureed</in>
<in>Cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>bay leaf#1</in>
<in>Cinnamon Sticks#2</in>
<in>Clove#2</in>
<in>Red Chilly Powder#To Taste</in>
<in>Coriander Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>Cumin Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>Kasoori Methi#1 tsp</in>
<in>Dry Mango Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>Turmeric Powder#Half tsp</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in>
<in>Oil#2tblsp</in>
<in>Cilantro#to Garnish</in><pr>Method
1. Soak the chik peas for 5-6 hours or overnight. Drain the soaking water.
2. Pressure cook the chik peas until they are tender (app. 2 cooker whistles). Overcooking will make it mushy.
3. Heat oil in a vessel over medium heat. Temper cumin seeds, bay leaves, clove and cinnamon. 
4. Saute onions, stirring frequently, until they are translucent.
5. Add ginger- garlic paste, and saute until the raw smell vanishes.
6. Add the tomato puree, chilly powder, coriander powder, cumin powder, kasoori methi, amchur powder, turmeric powder and salt and saute until a thick paste is formed.
7. Now add the chik peas along with the water in which it was cooked and let it simmer for 7 minutes. (Water can be added as per the requirement).
8. Garnish with cilantro and finely chopped onions. Serve with chappattis or bread.
</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Butter Chicken</ti>

<in>Chicken#Half Kg(bone,skinless)</in>
<in>Onion#1 Chopped</in>
<in>Tomato#3-4 Chopped</in>
<in>Cashew#5-6</in>
<in>Ginger Garlic Paste#2 tsp</in>
<in>Green Chilly#1 Chopped</in>
<in>Kasoori Methi#1 tsp</in>
<in>Fresh Cream#1 tsp</in>
<in>Chilly Powder#3/4 tsp</in>
<in>Coriander Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>Cumin Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>Turmeric#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>Garam Masala#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>Cumin seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Cilantro#Garnish</in>
<in>Butter#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Oil#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Salt#2 taste</in><pr>Method
1. Wash the turkey/chicken and cut it into 1 inch thick cubes. 
2. Apply little salt, chillypowder, coriander powder, kasoori methi and ginger garlic paste. Shallow fry in little oil and keep it aside. You can also put it in skewers and bake it in the oven.
     Tip :- To keep things simple, use 2 tblsp of tandoori chicken masala powder instead of all the individual spices (any brand is fine).
3. Heat some oil/butter in a pan and saute the onions followed by ginger garlic paste, green chilly and tomatoes.
4. When all these are nicely sauteed, remove from stove and let it cool a bit.
5. After it is cool enough to handle, grind everything in a blender/ mixie with the cashew nuts to make a paste.
6. Melt the butter in a pan, splutter some cumin seeds. Add this groud mixture and cook it for few minutes until the nuts gets cooked.
7. Next add the fried turkey/chicken pieces, with all the dry spices like chilly powder, coriander powder, turmeric powder, kasoori methi, garam masala and salt.
8. Cover and let it cook for 10-15 minutes in medium low flame so the flavours combine nicely.
9. Add the heavy cream, mix everything and let it simmer for few minutes.
10. Garnish with chopped cilantro or some cream and serve with pulav, naan, roti. It goes well with anything.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Chicken Tikka Masala</ti>

<in>Chicken#Half Kg</in>
<in>Tomato#1 Cup puree</in>
<in>Ginger Garlic Paste#1 tsp</in>
<in>Cashew#4-5 (made as paste)</in>
<in>Fresh Cream#3-4 tblsp</in>
<in>Oil#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Kasoori Methi#1 tsp</in>
<in>Coriander Powder#2 tsp</in>
<in>Garam Masala#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Red Chilly Powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Cumin seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Cilantro#To Garnish</in><pr>Heat a non stick pan with oil. Add ginger garlic paste and fry for 1 min in low flame.(monitor its not burnt)
3. Add the tomato puree and cook until it thickens to form a paste.
4. Now add garam masala, cayenne pepper, coriander powder and kasuri methi.
5. After 1 min add the heavy cream and stir in low flame to get a thick paste. Also add leftover marination masala(optional).
6. Now add the tikkas and cook for 2 mins and switch off.
7. Garnish with cilantro and serve with naan, chappathi or rice.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Idli</ti>

<in>Idli Rice#1 3/4 cup</in>
<in>Black Gram#1/2 cup</in>
<in>FenuGreek seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in><pr>Method 
1. Soak rice and black gram separately in water for atleast 1 hour. Soaking overnight can be done too. Add fenugreek seeds to black gram.
2. Drain the water and grind the black gram to a silky soft texture.
3. Next grind the rice coarsely. Mix it with black gram batter along with salt.
4. Now leave the batter to rest and ferment for atleast 6 hours till the batter rises to almost double the size.
5. Grease the idli plates with few drops of oil and fill with idli batter.
6. Steam them for about 10 minutes till they rise and become firm. (If you do not have idli stand, grease stainless steel tumblers,  fill it with batter and steam it as shown in the picture.)
7. Switch off the stove and let it rest for a minute or 2. After that use a wet spoon to remove the idlis from the idli plate</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Dosa</ti>

<in>Rice#3.5 cups</in>
<in>Urad Dal#1 cup</in>
<in>Fenugreek seeds#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Oil#To Fry</in>
<in>Salt#To Taste</in><pr>1. Wash and soak the rice and urad dal with bengalgram dal and fenugreek seeds separately or together . Traditionally it used to soaked separately and ground separately. But with modern mixies and grinders you can grind everything together itself.
2. Similarly overnight soaking is good. But for urgent situations, even 1 hour of soaking will do for modern mixies and grinders.
3. After soaking, drain and grind it to a smooth paste with salt and water enough to make a batter little thinner than idli batter. If the batter becomes thicker you can always add water later. 
4. Let this batter ferment overnight till it raises to double its size.
5. Grease a non stick dosa pan and pour a spoonful of batter. Spread it using the back of the spoon using circular motion to about 9 inch round dosa.
6. Add few drops of oil on top. 
7. Once it turns slightly brown, flip and brown the other side too.
8. Serve hot with sambhar, chutney or any non veg gravy.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Parotta</ti>

<in>maida#2 cups</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in>
<in>Warm Water#1/2 cup</in>
<in>Oil#1/2 Cup</in><pr>Method
1. Mix the maida, salt and warm water and Knead to form dough. Cover the dough with a wet kitchen towel and let it rest for 1/2 - 1 hour.
2. Knead the dough again adding 2-3 tblsp of oil little at a time. Continue kneading the dough for 10-15 minutes till you get a soft and elastic dough. You can use the dough attachment of your grinder or a kitchen aid to make this task easier.
3. Divide the dough into small balls - 5-6 balls and leave it under the moist towel.
4. Take a dough ball and roll it out into a very thin layer as thin as possible. The dough may bounce back as you roll. Use oil for easily rolling out the dough(Do not use flour). You should be able to see the rolling surface through the stretched rolled out dough.
5. Apply a layer of oil all over the rolled out dough. Beginning with one side, fold it over and under alternatively just like making a paper fan or saree pleets.
6.Tap this folded dough on the rolling surface holding both ends with your hands. This will expand and stretch the dough lengthwise.
7. Now roll it from both ends towards the center. When it meets in the center, place one side of roll on top of the other.
8. Repeat the process for every dough ball and place it under the moist kitchen towel. In the meantime, heat a tava on medium high flame.
9. Now roll out each of the above pleeted and rolled dough and roll it again using a rolling pin.
10. Fry these on the tava with enough oil till you see brown spots on both sides.
11. Once all the parottas are done, line up the parottas one above the other. Beat it with both of your hands on the sides when it is still hot to seperate the layers.
12. Serve hot with chicken kurma, veg kurma, chalna, mutton curry, beef curry or spicy chicken curry.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Sweet Pongal</ti>

<in>Raw Rice#1 cup</in>
<in>Moong Dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>Jaggery#1.5 cup(crushed)</in>
<in>Ghee#1/4 cup</in>
<in>Water#4 cups</in>
<in>cardamom powder#1/2 ts[</in>
<in>Cashew#To Taste</in>
<in>Almond#To taste</in>
<in>Saffron#A pinch</in><pr>Method
1. Take a pressure cooker and dry roast the moong dal for about 5 minutes.
2. Add the rice to this. Now add the 4 cups of water (with milk if adding) and 1 tsp ghee.
3. Pressure cook for 3-4 whistles till the rice and dal is cooked soft. You can also cook the mixture in a rice cooker or an open pot.
4. In the meantime, heat 1 tblsp of ghee and fry the nuts and raisins. Keep this aside.
5. Next, melt the crushed jaggery with 1 cup of water in a heavy bottmoned pot/pan.
6. Once the jaggery has melted, you can strain it to remove any dirt. This step can be skipped if the jaggery is pure.
7. Return the strained jaggery back to the pot. Bring it to a boil, reduce the heat and let it simmer for about 5 minutes.
8. Mash the cooked rice-dal mixture partially and add it to the simmering jaggery syrup.
9. Add the remaining ghee, cardamom powder, saffron strands and the roasted nuts. Mix together and let it simmer for few minutes till everything comes together into a gooey pongal consistency. 
10. Switch off. The pongal continues to thicken as it cools. Serve as a snack, dessert or a meal. </pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Curd Rice</ti>

<in>Rice#1 Cup</in>
<in>Water#3 Cups</in>
<in>Milk#Cold 1.5 Cup</in>
<in>Curd#1.5Cup</in>
<in>Cream#2tblsp</in>
<in>Salt#as needed</in>
<in>Dry Red Chilly#2</in>
<in>Green Chilly#3</in>
<in>Mustard seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Curry leaves#1</in><pr>Method
1. Cook the rice with 3 cups of water and some salt. We need overcooked rice which gets easily mashed up.
   Tip :- If you have leftover rice, just reheat it with some additional water.
2. Once the rice is cooked, mix and mash up part of the rice.
3. Add the milk and keep mixing till all the milk gets absorbed by the rice.
4. Once you add the cold milk, the rice will cool down. If it is still hot, wait for it to become luke warm before you add the curd. This will prevent the curd from curdling.
5. Add the cream and yogurt and mix well. 
6. Heat oil for tempering in a small pan and splutter the mustard seeds.
7. Add the chana dal and urad dal and wait for it to turn reddish brown.
8. Now add the dry red chillyes, curry leaves, finely chopped green chillyes and finely chopped ginger. Fry for a minute. (You can add some raisins and cashews too.)
9. Add this to the curd rice. Also add the finely chooped corriander leaves and mix together.
10. Curd rice is ready to be served. You can also garnish it with more chopped cilantro or grated carrots or chopped cucumber or fresh fruits like pineapple, pomegranate, grapes, apples etc.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Medhu vadai</ti>

<in>Split Black Gram#1 cup</in>
<in>Ginger#1 inch piece</in>
<in>Green Chilly#3-4</in>
<in>Dry Red Chilly#3</in>
<in>Black Pepper#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Asafoetida#a pinch</in>
<in>Curry leaves#1-2 Strand</in>
<in>Oil#For Deep Fry</in>
<in>Salt#To taste</in>
<in>Onion#1/2 Chopped</in>
<in>Cumin seeds#1/2 tsp</in><pr>Method
1. Soak the urad dal overnight or a minimum of 1/2 an hour.
2. Drain the water and grind the dal in grinder/blender/mixie using as little water as possible.

3. Take this urad dal batter in a bowl and add required salt, grated ginger, green/red chillyes, crushed pepper, asafoetida and chopped curry leaves.
4. You could add in the optional ingredients too if you prefer. Mix the batter nicely.
5. In the meantime, heat the oil for frying the vadas.
6. To shape the vadas, wet your hand, take a small portion of batter on the palm your hand.
7. Using the finger of your other hand or the thumb of the same hand, make a small hole in the center of the batter.
8. Gently slide the batter into the hot oil. The hole helps in even cooking of the vadas inside and out. The vadas should be fried in medium heat.
9. Once the vadas get golden brown on one side, flip it and cook the other side.
10. Once the vada fully turns golden brown, remove it and let it rest on paper towels to remove excess oil.
11. Serve hot with coconut chutney or sambar all by itself or with any south indian breakfast items like idli, pongal etc.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Rasam</ti>

<in>Tamarind#lime sized</in>
<in>Tomato#1 finely Chopped crushed</in>
<in>Garlic#3-4 clove</in>
<in>Green Chilly#1</in>
<in>Turmeric Powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>Water#3 cups</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in>
<in>Oil#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Mustard seeds#1/2 Tsp</in>
<in>Curry leaves#7 leaves</in>
<in>Asafoetida Powder#1/2tsp</in>
<in>Black Pepper#3 tsp</in>
<in>Toor Dal#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Red Chilly#2</in><pr>Method 
1. Dry roast and grind everything under 'rasam powder ingredients' very coarsely. This is the Rasam powder.
2. Soak the tamarind in warm water for 5 minutes to get tamarind juice.
3. Heat little oil in a pan, add the garlic, green chilly and tomatoes. Let the tomatoes cook for while, until they become soft and juicy.
4. Now add tamarind juice,  turmeric, salt, cilantro and water.
5. Bring it to a boil then reduce the flame.
6. Add the rasam powder and asafoetida. Let it simmer for about 5 minutes. Do not let it boil.
7. In the meanwhile, heat oil in pan, add  mustard seeds and curry leaves.
8. Once it splutters add it to the rasam. Garnish with some fresh chopped cilantro. Tasty rasam is ready to serve. Plain rice with rasam and paapad is an excellent combination. </pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Mor Kulambu/Butter Milk</ti>

<in>Rice#1 tsp</in>
<in>Toor Dal#2 tsp</in>
<in>Ginger#Small pc</in>
<in>Green Chilly#4</in>
<in>Cumin seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Curd#1 cup</in>
<in>Lime Juice#as per taste</in>
<in>Mustard seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>Curry leaves#1 strand</in>
<in>Dry Red Chilly#2</in>
<in>Tomato#1/4</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in><pr>Method
1. Grind the ingredients from batch I(first 5)very well.
2. Now add the curd and grind it for about a min.
3. In a pan put oil for seasoning, put mustard seeds, curryleaves and dry red Chilly.
4. Then add tomato if needed.
5. Now add okra and fry it 3 min and add water and let it cook.
6. Once the okra is cooked add the curd mixture, add required salt and allow is to get warm. 
7. Take the pan off the stove before boiling to prevent the curd from curdling.
8. It's yummy with rice, fried and spicy veggies.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Mango Thokku/Pickle</ti>

<in>Mango#2 cups Grated</in>
<in>Red Chilly Powder#2 tsp</in>
<in>Asafoetida#A pinch</in>
<in>Salt#A tsp</in>
<in>Curry leaves#taste</in>
<in>Turmeric Powder#1/2 Tsp</in>
<in>Fenugreek seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Oil#5 tblsp</in>
<in>Mustard seeds#1 tsp</in><pr>Method:
1. Heat the oil in a kadai. Add mustard seeds, fenugreek seeds, asafoetida. 
2. After it splutters, add the grated mango, turmeric powder  and saute  the same  till it becomes tender. 
3. Take out from the gas and allow to cool.   
4. Add the chilly powder, salt and mix well. Transfer it to a glass bottle or bharani.

Serve with dal rice, curd rice, dosa etc.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Chicken Burrito</ti>

<in>Chicken#Boneless Skinless Breasts 2</in>
<in>Tortilla#4</in>
<in>beans#2 cups</in>
<in>Chilly Powder#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Coriander Powder#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Tomato#1</in>
<in>Salsa#3 tblsp</in>
<in>Cheese#As needed</in>
<in>Sour Cream#To Garnish</in>
<in>Green Chilly#2-3</in>
<in>Oil#1 tblsp</in>
<in>Cilantro#Garnish</in><pr>Method
1. Cook the chicken breast separately, shread it into small pieces.
2. Take a pan, heat some oil and fry up the shredded chicken. Remove and set aside.
3. Heat some more oil in the same pan. Add the cooked beans with little water.
4. Add any seasoning mix according to your taste. I made it indian style with little chilly powder, coriander powder, garam masala and salt. Let it cook for 2 minutes.
5. Add the shredded chicken, salsa and cheese to this and mix everything. Switch off after everything blends well.
6. Take a flour tortilla and heat it on a griddle or microwave as per package directions.
7. Place the filling in the middle and garnish with some fresh chopped tomatoes, green chillyes, cilantro and sour cream.
8. Fold it as shown in the picture.
 </pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Quesadilla</ti>

<in>Tortilla#Large Flour</in>
<in>Cheese#Grated</in>
<in>Olive Oil#2 tblsp</in>
<in>Mushroom#2 Sliced</in>
<in>Onion#2 Sliced</in>
<in>Pepper#to taste</in>
<in>Garam Masala# to taste</in>
<in>Salt#to taste</in><pr>Method
1. Saute all the stuffing ingredients of your choice with little salt, peppr and garam masala and keep aside. You can even use without sauteeing.
2. Heat a large frying pan/griddle to medium high heat. Add 1/2 tsp of oil/butter and spread it. 
3. Place a tortilla in the pan. Flip the tortilla over a few times until it is nicely warmed and small bubbles are formed.
4.Take a handful of grated cheese and sprinkle over the top of the tortilla.at the cheese does not land on the pan itself.
5.Add little of the sauteed mixture (about 2 tblsp) over the cheese.
6. Put some more cheese on top and top it with another tortilla.
7. Reduce the heat to low and cover the pan. After a minute flip and leave it for another minute or so until the cheese melts inside and the tortillas are nicely browned. 
8. Remove from pan and cut into wedges. Serve with some iceberg lettuce, salsa, sour cream, ketchup or guacamole. </pr></recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>Kootu Curry</ti>

<in>Yam#200 grams</in>
<in>Plantain#3</in>
<in>Bengal Gram#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>Turmeric Powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>Chilly Powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>Jaggery#3/4 tsp</in>
<in>Salt#To taste</in>
<in>Coconut#1/3 cup grated</in>
<in>Red Chilly#2</in>
<in>Cumin seeds#3/4 tsp</in>
<in>Mustard seeds#q tsp</in>
<in>Red Chilly#1</in>
<in>Curry leaves#Few</in><pr>Method
1. Soak the chana dal for 15 minutes in warm water and pressure cook till soft. 
2. Peel the skin and chop the raw banana  and yam into medium size pieces.
3. Grind coconut, red chilly and cumin seeds coarsely and keep it aside. 
4. Cook both banana and yam with turmeric powder, salt and chilly powder  until soft.
5. Add the cooked bengal gram and jaggery to the above. 
6. Then add the grounded paste and boil till it thickens. 
7. Now heat a tsp of oil, add mustard seeds, when it splutters, add red chilly and curry leaves. Pour this seasoning over the koottu curry. 
8. Fry coconut till it becomes golden brown and add to the kootu curry. 
9. Serve this with rice. This is part of the traditional Sadya.</pr></recipe><recipe>
<ti>Puli Inghi/Tamarind Ginger Pickle</ti>

<in>Tamarind#1 big sized</in>
<in>Green Chilly#10</in>
<in>Ginger#Medium size</in>
<in>Jaggery#2 pieces</in>
<in>Turmeric Powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>Salt#As needed</in>
<in>Oil#2tblsp</in>
<in>Curry leaves#few</in>
<in>Fenugreek seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>Bengal Gram#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>Asafoetida#1/4 tsp</in><pr>Method
1. Soak the tamarind in hot water and extract the juice 
2. Heat 2 tsp oil in a kadai, add the mustard seeds, fenugreek seeds and chana dal.
3. When it splutters, add the chopped green chilly, ginger and curry leaves. Saute for a minute.
4. Add the tamarind pulp, turmeric powder, salt, jaggery  and boil
5. Boil it till it starts reducing and you get a semi solid inchi puli. 
6. Add the asafoetida. Remove from the gas.</pr></recipe>
	<recipe>
		<ti>Almond Joy Candy</ti>
		<in>milk#1 cn Condensed  sweetened 14 oz</in>
		<in>Chocolate#2 oz  unsweetened</in>
		<in>Salt#1/4 ts </in>
		<in>Vanilla#1 ts</in>
		<in>Coconut#3 c  shredded</in>
		<in>Almond#45 whole, salted</in>
		<pr>Preheat oven to 350F. In top of double boiler, combine condensed milk,
chocolate and salt. Cook over rapidly boiling water; stirring often, for 5
to 7 minutes, or till until mixture thickens. Remove from heat and stir in
vanilla and coconut. Form cookies by dropping teaspoons of mixture on well
greased baking sheet, 1" apart. Top each with a whole almond. Bake on
middle sheet of oven for 10-12 minutes, watching cookies carefully after
8-9 minutes,as the bottom can get too brown. Immediately remove cookies
from pan with metal spatula and cool on wax peper covered rack.
</pr>
	</recipe>
		<recipe>
		<ti>Almond Roca Cookies</ti>
		<in>Butter#1 c </in>
		<in>Brown sugar#1/2 c </in>
		<in>Sugar#1/22 c</in>
		<in>Egg#1 yolk</in>
		<in>Vanilla#1 ts </in>
		<in>Flour#2 c </in>
		<in>Chocolate#10 oz  chips</in>
		<in>nuts#1 c Finely chopped </in>
		<pr>Cream butter and sugar, add egg yolk and vanilla. Stir in flour.
Spread mixture thinly on greased cookie sheet. Bake at 350 degrees for 15
to 20 minutes. Melt chocolate over hot water and spread over warm baked
cookies. Sprinkle on nuts and press them firmly. Cut in bars while still
warm. Let stand until chocolate is dry.
</pr>
	</recipe>
		<recipe>
		<ti>Bermuda Chicken</ti>
		<in>chicken#4  Boneless  breast halves</in>
		<in>Olive oil#2 tb </in>
		<in>Shallot#1 minced</in>
		<in>bread#1 c Dry crumbs</in>
		<in>Parsley#3 tb  chopped</in>
		<in>Thyme#1/4 ts  or 3/4 tsp. fresh, minced</in>
		<in>Rosemary#1/8 ts  crumbled, or 1/2 tsp. fresh, minced</in>
		<in>Egg#1  Egg yolk</in>
		<pr>Place chicken breasts between two sheets of wax paper and pound lightly
with a mallet or other heavy flat object to flatten to 1/4 inch thick. Heat
1 tsp. oil in a heavy nonstick skillet over medium low heat. SautÂ_ shallot
1-2 minutes or until softened. Transfer shallot to a bowl and set aside.
Stir next 4 ingredients and salt and pepper to taste into bowl with
shallot. Add 1/2 tsp. oil and egg yolk and lightly toss. Heat remaining oil
in same skillet over medium high heat. SautÂ_ chicken 3 minutes per side.
Turn on broiler. Place chicken breasts on an ovenproof platter. Press a
portion of crumb mixture onto one side of each chicken breast until
breadcrumb mixture is 1/4 inch thick. Place chicken on broiler pan, crumb
side up, and broil 1 minute or until golden. Serve crumb side up.
This recipe serves 4 people. Because this recipe is for a particular size
pan, it adjusts the number of servings only in multiples of 4.
</pr></recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>green dosa</ti>
<in>green gram# 2 cups</in>
<in>rice# 4 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly# 5-7</in>
<in>ginger# 2" piece</in>
<in>jeera# 2 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Soak the green gram and rice for atleast 1 hour and drain the water. Longer soaking would be good.
2. Add this soaked lentil and rice to a mixie/blender along with the ginger piece and green chillies.
3. Add enough water and required salt and grind to a smooth paste.
4. Remove the batter and mix the cumin seeds with it.
5. Heat a griddle/ dosa pan. Check if it is hot enough by sprinkling few drops of water. The water will sizzle right away.
6. Pour a laddlefull of batter in the center and spread it into a nice round shape using the back of the spoon.
7. Sprinkle few chopped onions and few drops of oil on top.
8. After it turns golden brown at the bottom, flip it over.
9. After it gets cooked on both sides, remove from the griddle.
10. Serve piping hot with upma and chutney (peanut chutney or ginger chutney or coconut chutney). 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>rava dosa</ti>
<in>rava# 1 cup</in>
<in>rice flour# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>maida# 2 tsp</in>
<in>buttermilk# 1 cup</in>
<in>onion# 1</in>
<in>jeera# 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>black pepper# 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly# 1</in>
<in>ginger# 1"</in>
<in>cilantro# 2-3 strands</in>
<in>curry leaves# 1 strand</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Mix the rava, rice flour, maida and required salt.
2. Add finely chopped onions, green chilly, cilantro, curry leaves, grated ginger, cumin seeds and crushed black pepper to that.
3. Add the yogurt/buttermilk and required water to make a batter thinner than normal dosa batter. Let the batter rest for 10-15 minutes.
4. Heat a non stick dosa pan on medium high heat. 
5. Take a spoon ful of batter and spread the batter from the outer side of the pan. (unlike the normal dosa which you spread from the inside out.)
6. Pour few drops of oil on top and let it cook for a couple of minutes on one side. 
7. Gently flip the dosa and cook until both the sides are golden brown.
8. Serve with coconut chutney and sambhar. You can also stuff it with masala and make rava masala dosa.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>ginger chutney</ti>
<in>ginger# 2" piece</in>
<in>bengal gram# 2 tsp</in>
<in>black gram# 2 tsp</in>
<in>coriander seeds# 2 tsp</in>
<in>jeera# 3/4 tsp</in>
<in>tamarind# big lemon size</in>
<in>green chilly# 4-5</in>
<in>dry red chilly# 3-5</in>
<in>sugar# 1 tsp</in>
<in>oil# 3 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Heat oil in a pan and fry chana dal, urad dal, coriander seeds, cumin seeds, dry red chillies and green chillies for 3-4 minutes until the dals turn golden brown.
2. Add the ginger pieces and tamarind and fry for another 2-3. (Make sure the flame is in medium to prevent the ingredients from getting burnt.)
3. After the mixture cools, grind it in a mixie with required water, salt and jaggery.
4. Serve with pesarattu, vada, upma etc. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>hyderabadi biryani</ti>
<in>basmati rice# 3 cups</in>
<in>onion# 3</in>
<in>green chilly# 6 + 10 slit</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>garlic</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>fennel powder# 3/4 tsp</in>
<in>coconut milk# 1 cup</in>
<in>water# 3 cups</in>
<in>ghee# 4 tsp</in>
<in>chicken# 2 lbs</in>
<in>tomato# 3</in>
<in>mint# 1 cup leaves</in>
<in>cilantro# 1 cup</in>
<in>curd# 4 tsp</in>
<in>jeera# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>coriander powder# 2 tsp</in>
<in>chilly powder# 2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>pepper powder# 1 tsp</in>
<in>garam masala# 1 tsp</in>
<in>bay leaf# 1</in>
<in>cinnamon# 2 sticks</in>
<in>clove# 5</in>
<in>cardamom# 3</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
To Prepare Rice
1. Soak the rice in water for about half an hour.
2. Heat little ghee in a frying pan, add the onions and green chilllies and fry till it turns brown in colour.
3. Add the ginger garlic paste and fry for a minute.
4. Add fennel powder and the drained rice. Fry the rice for few minutes.
5. Add the coconut milk, water and required salt and let it cook till the rice is 3/4th cooked.
 
To make gravy
1. Heat the ghee in a pan and add the whole garam masala.
2. Add the onions, green chillies and mint leaves and saute.
3. Add the ginger garlic paste and fry till the mixture is golden brown.
4. Add the tomatoes and cook till the tomatoes are smashed up.
5. Add all the dry spice powders, salt and curd. Cook the mixture.
6. Add the chicken pieces and saute nicely.
7. Cover, cook for 10 minutes and switch off. The chicken gravy is ready.
 
To prepare Dhum
Method 1 (On Stove top)
1. Take a heavy bottomed vessel and add about 2 inches of the prepared gravy.
2. Add half of the cooked rice as the next layer.
3. Next layer with the remaining gravy and put the remaining cooked rice as the last layer.
4. Top this with chopped cilantro, fried onions and roasted cashews.
5. Mix the orange food colour/saffron with the lemon juice and sprinkle on top. 
6. Cover with a tight fitting lid. 
7. Keep a tawa on the stove-top and put this vessel on top of it.
8. Keep the flame on a very low setting and cook for about half an hour.
 
Method 2 (In the oven)
1. Take a baking dish or aluminium tray and add the chicken gravy as the first layer.
2. Add the half cooked rice as the second layer and top it with chopped cilantro, fried onions and roasted cashews.
3. Mix the orange food colour/saffron with the lemon juice and sprinkle on top.
4. Cover the dish/tray with aluminium foil and cook it in a 350 degree oven for half an hour.

- Do not mix it. While serving dig deep with the serving spoon to get all the layers.
- Serve with raita, boiled egg, mirchi ka salan or ennai kathirikai. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>chicken kurma</ti>
<in>chicken# 1 lb</in>
<in>onion# 1</in>
<in>kuskus# 2 tsp</in>
<in>cashew# 4</in>
<in>coriander seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly# 5-7 tsp</in>
<in>jeera# 1 tsp</in>
<in>coconut# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>curd# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>garlic</in>
<in>cardamom# 3</in>
<in>fennel seeds# 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>bay leaf# 1</in>
<in>clove# 2</in>
<in>cinnamon# 1 stick</in>
<in>oil# 2 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Soak kuskus in 1 cup warm water for 10 minutes and then grind it with green chillies, coriander seeds, cumin seeds, cashews,cardamom and coconut. Keep it aside.
2. Heat oil in a deep pan. Splutter fennel seeds.Add the bay leaf, clove and cinnamon.
3. Add sliced onions and fry them till they are translucent. Next add the ginger-garlic paste and saute till the raw smell vanishes. 
3. Add the chicken/turkey pieces and saute for 2 minutes. Next add 1 cup water, yogurt and salt to it. Cover and cook till the chicken is almost done.
4. At this stage add the ground paste and add the water required. Check for salt and let the kurma simmer for 5 minutes.
5. Garnish with cilantro. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>ladiesfinger curry</ti>
<in>ladiesfinger# 1/2 lb</in>
<in>onion</in>
<in>tomato# 1</in>
<in>tamarind</in>
<in>sambar powder# 3/2 tsp</in>
<in>garlic# 3-4 pods</in>
<in>curry leaves# 1 string</in>
<in>mustard seeds# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>methi seeds# 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>oil# 2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric# 2 pinches</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Warm the kadai with oil and add thalippu (thaduka) with mustard seeds, methi seeds and curry leaves. 
2. Add the sliced onion, okra and garlic, sauté it. 
3. Add the chopped tomato and sauté it with salt, turmeric and kulambu powder. 
4. Add the tamarind water. 
5. Let it cook for 10- 15 mins.on medium heat until oil separates. 
6. Serve it with steamed rice and appalam. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>sweet pongal</ti>
<in>rice# 1 cup</in>
<in>moong dal# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>jaggery# 3/2 cups</in>
<in>ghee# 1/4 cup</in>
<in>water# 5 cups</in>
<in>cardamom powder# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>cashew</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Take a pressure cooker and dry roast the moong dal for about 5 minutes.
2. Add the rice to this. Now add the 4 cups of water (with milk if adding) and 1 tsp ghee.
3. Pressure cook for 3-4 whistles till the rice and dal is cooked soft. You can also cook the mixture in a rice cooker or an open pot.
4. In the meantime, heat 1 tblsp of ghee and fry the nuts and raisins. Keep this aside.
5. Next, melt the crushed jaggery with 1 cup of water in a heavy bottmoned pot/pan.
6. Once the jaggery has melted, you can strain it to remove any dirt. This step can be skipped if the jaggery is pure.
7. Return the strained jaggery back to the pot. Bring it to a boil, reduce the heat and let it simmer for about 5 minutes.
8. Mash the cooked rice-dal mixture partially and add it to the simmering jaggery syrup.
9. Add the remaining ghee, cardamom powder, saffron strands and the roasted nuts. Mix together and let it simmer for few minutes till everything comes together into a gooey pongal consistency. 
10. Switch off. The pongal continues to thicken as it cools. Serve as a snack, dessert or a meal. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>mutton ridgegourd curry</ti>
<in>mutton# 500 gms</in>
<in>ridgegourd# 150 gms</in>
<in>oil# 2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder# 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly powder# 1 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>onion</in>
<in>clove</in>
<in>pepper powder</in>
<in>coconut paste# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>coriander leaves# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>garlic paste# 1 tsp</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Heat oil in a pan or clay pot. 
2. Add the onion paste with turmeric powder. Fry until brown.
3. Add the mutton pieces. Mix chilli powder and cook for 20 minutes.
4. Next add the ridgegourd pieces with clove and pepper powder.
5. Finally mix in the coconut paste with salt. Cook for a while.
6. Before serving add coriander leaves. This is a tasty dish.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>chicken curry</ti>
<in>chicken# 1 kg</in>
<in>turmeric powder# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>chilly powder# 2 tsp</in>
<in>garam masala# 1 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>onion paste# 1 cup</in>
<in>ginger paste# 2 tsp</in>
<in>tamarind paste# 2 tsp</in>
<in>coriander powder# 1 tsp</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Marinate the chicken by mixing haldi, chilli powder, coriander powder and ginger paste for half an hour.
2. Heat oil in a pan. Fry onion paste until brown.
3. After that add the marinated chicken and cook for half an hour.
4. Finally add tamarind paste, garam masala and salt.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>egg curry</ti>
<in>egg# 5</in>
<in>onion paste#1 cup</in>
<in>coconut paste#1/2 cup</in>
<in>turmeric powder# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>tamarind paste# 2 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly paste# 2 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil# 2 tsp</in>
<in>garam masala# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>coriander leaves# 1/2 cup</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Heat oil in a clay pot. If it is prepared in clay pot, it will be tasty.
2. Fry the onion paste until brown.
3. Add the coconut paste. Cook for 5 minutes.
4. Mix the tamarind paste and chilli paste in it. If you need to add water, you may add 1 cup of water.
5. Add the boiled eggs in it.
6. Finally add garam masala, coriander levaes and salt.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>eggplant fry</ti>
<in>eggplant# 1</in>
<in>chilly powder# 1 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder</in>
<in>garam masala</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>lemon# 1/2</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Cut the eggplant into thin circles.
2. Season the eggplant circles with the above seasonings.
3. Shallow fry the eggplant in a griddle.
4. Flip the eggplant when once side browns.
5. When both the sides are browned, remove from griddle and add few drops of lemon juice on top.
6. Serve with rice or roti. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>aloo posto</ti>
<in>potato# 5-6</in>
<in>poppy seeds# 4 tsp</in>
<in>onion seeds# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly# 2</in>
<in>sugar# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>ghee# 1 tsp</in>
<in>mustard oil# 2 tsp</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Take off the skin and cut the potatoes into cubes. Keep them in water.
2· Grind the poppy seeds to a fine paste.
3· Heat up mustard oil in a kadai (pot) till it just reaches smoking point.
4. Heat up the oil. Pour  kalonji and 1 chilly  and stir-fry.
5· Add  potato pieces and stir fry on medium heat up until the potatoes get some golden colour, stirring frequently.
6· Mix in the poppy seeds paste, stir and mix in half cup of water, cover and stir fry on low heat up till the potatoes are almost done.
7· Take off the lid, mix in salt, sugar and slit green chillies.
8· Continue to stir fry for a minute more or till potatoes are completely cooked, stir in desi ghee and serve hot.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>Steamed Hilsa</ti>
<in>hilsa fish# 500 gms</in>
<in>mustard</in>
<in>mustard oil# 3-4 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly# 2</in>
<in>turmeric powder</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>onion seeds# 1/2 tsp</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Wash the fish. Coat the fish with  turmeric powder and salt. Keep it aside and let it marinate for 15 minutes.
2. Make a paste of mustard and turmeric powder with some water.
3. Heat a pan with 2-3 tblsp of mustard  oil. Put ½ tblsp of Kalonji (onion Seeds) and 2 green chillies.
4. Add the paste and stir for a minute. Next add the fishes.
5. Pour 2 cups of water. Cover and let it cook for about 10-15 minutes. (You can also pressure cook for 2 whistles.)
6. Let the gravy thicken.
7. Drizzle 1 tbsp of mustard oil and 2-3 green chillies. Serve with steamed rice.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>sukto</ti>
<in>bittergourd# 1</in>
<in>ridgegourd# 1</in>
<in>brinjal# 1</in>
<in>banana# 1</in>
<in>potato# 1</in>
<in>sweet potato# 1</in>
<in>drumstick# 3</in>
<in>pointedgourd# 3</in>
<in>papaya# 150 gms</in>
<in>radish# 1</in>
<in>carrot# 1</in>
<in>milk# 1/3 cup</in>
<in>mustard oil</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>ghee</in>
<in>mustard seeds# 2 tsp</in>
<in>poppy seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<in>ginger# 1 tsp</in>
<in>bay leaf# 4</in>
<in>wild celery# 1 tsp</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. To make ideal sukto, cut all the vegetables in uniform size (about 1 ½ inches long).
2. Make a paste of mustard and poppy seeds. Also make a paste of ginger.
3. Heat oil in a kadai and fry the bari (vadi). Keep it aside.
4. Heat mustard oil in a pan. Fry all the vegetables till half done. Keep them aside.
5. Add the bay leaf and wild celery to the hot oil. Let it crackle. 
6. Add the ginger paste and mustard-poppy paste. Stir fry for 3 minutes.
7. Add all the vegetables and fry.
8. Add the vadi(bori) and required salt. Mix them well.
9. Add water as required. Cover the pan with a lid and cook for about 10 minutes in low heat.
10. Add Milk and ghee and cook again for 5 minutes in low heat.
11. Switch off and serve hot with steamed rice. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>pepper shukto</ti>
<in>papaya# 1</in>
<in>milk# 3/2 cups</in>
<in>bay leaf# 2</in>
<in>fenugreek seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<in>vadi# 10-15</in>
<in>oil# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>sugar</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>white mustard seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<in>poppy seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Cut the papaya into small pieces and cook it till it becomes soft. Drain the excess water and keep aside.
2. Make a paste of mustard seeds and poppy seeds. Keep it aside.
3. Heat the kadai, pour some oil and fry the Vadis (Bori). Keep it aside.
4. Pour 2 tblsp oil and add the fenugreek seeds. Let it crackle. Remove it from the oil.
5. Now add the bay leaves into the same oil. Add the mustard seeds and poppy seeds paste. Mix well. 
6. Now add the boiled papaya, salt, bori and sugar. Mix it well. Cook for 5 minutes. 
7. Now add the milk and cover it with a lid. Cook again for 10 minutes.
Serve with rice.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>bengali chicken curry</ti>
<in>chicken# 500 gms</in>
<in>onion# 500 gms</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>garlic# 15 clove</in>
<in>chilly paste# 1 tsp</in>
<in>tomato# 2</in>
<in>chilly# 10-12</in>
<in>turmeric powder# 2 tsp</in>
<in>jeera# 1 tsp</in>
<in>chilly powder# 1 tsp</in>
<in>mustard oil# 1 cup</in>
<in>curd# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Wash chicken pieces and apply some oil, salt and turmeric powder on it. Let it marinate for half an hour.
2. Heat the remaining oil in a kadai and fry the onions till golden brown. 
3. Next add the garlic clove, 5-6 green chillies and tomatoes.
4. Add salt, turmeric powder, cumin powder, chilly powder, ginger garlic and green chilly paste one by one. Keep stirring and cook till it becomes brown in colour.
5. Now add the chicken pieces and mix. Cover and cook for about 30 minutes till it softens. Keep stirring often. If the chicken starts sticking to the bottom, splash some water.
6. Finally add the curd and mix. Switch off. Serve hot with rice or chapatti.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>achari murg</ti>
<in>chicken# 1 kg</in>
<in>dry red chilly# 10</in>
<in>carom seeds# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>onion# 3</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>garlic</in>
<in>tomato# 4</in>
<in>green chilly# 6</in>
<in>turmeric powder# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly powder# 1 tsp</in>
<in>yogurt# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>lemon juice# 2 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>garlic pickle# 2-3 tsp</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>mustard oil# 2-3 tsp</in>
<in>mustard seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<in>onion seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<in>fenugreek seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<in>jeera# 1 tsp</in>
<in>fennel seeds# 1 tsp</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Wash the chicken pieces nicely. Add some salt, lemon juice and slit green chillies to the chicken. Let this marinate while we get the other things ready. 
2. Heat oil in a kadai and add the seasoning ingredients (paanch pooran).
3. Add the dry red chillies and carom seeds.
4. Add the chopped onion and saute till it turns golden brown.
5. Next fry the ginger garlic paste. Add the pureed tomato.
6. Add the red chilly powder, salt, turmeric powder, pickle and let it cook till oil seperates from the masala.
7. Add the chicken pieces and saute till the masala coats the chicken and the outside of the chicken is cooked.
8. Cover and reduce the flame. Let the chicken cook in its own juices for 15-20 minutes. Splash some water only if the chicken sticks to the bottom of the pan.
9. Check for seasoning. Adjust salt, chilly powder and lemon juice according to your taste.
10. Garnish with cilantro and switch off. Serve with any roti or white rice.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>12 spice fish curry</ti>
<in>fish# 1 lb</in>
<in>tamarind# 2-3</in>
<in>tomato# 1</in>
<in>asafoetida# 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>mustard seeds# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>curry leaves# 1 strand</in>
<in>oil# 3-4 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly# 2</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>coconut# 4 tsp</in>
<in>coriander seeds# 3 tsp</in>
<in>sambar onion# 5-6</in>
<in>garlic# 6 clove</in>
<in>ginger# 1/4" piece</in>
<in>dry red chilly# 7</in>
<in>pepper# 6 seeds</in>
<in>turmeric powder# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>jeera# 1 tsp</in>
<in>curry leaves# 2 strands</in>
<in>carom seeds# 1/4 tsp</in>
<in>fenugreek seeds# 5-8</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Heat oil in a small pan and roast the grated coconut with the onions, garlic, ginger and dry red chillies till the coconut turns nice and brown. Set aside to cool.
2. Similarly roast the corriander seeds, black peppercons, curry leaves, cumin seeds, fenugreek seeds and carom seeds too. ( Roasting each ingredient seperately is better but if you do not have time, you can roast everything together.)
3. Once everything cools grind everything together (all the spices under ingredients -2) to a fine paste and keep aside.
4. Heat little oil in a clay pot/deep pan. If you are adding any veggies, saute the veggies and tomato pieces till it is partly mashed up.
5. Add the ground spice masala, asafoetida and tamarind juice. Add required water and bring it to a boil.
6. Check for salt and add the fish pieces. Cover and cook it for 5-10 minutes.
7. Reduce the flame to the lowest and let the gravy simmer for another 15-20 minutes till the oil seperates from the gravy.
8. Heat little coconut/sesame oil in a pan and splutter the mustard seeds and curry leaves. Add this to the gravy.
9. Garnish with finely chopped cilantro and split green chillies. The final curry should have equal amout of spiciness from the masala, tanginess from the tamarind and salt.
10. Let the gravy rest for 2 hours before serving for the spices to enter the fish pieces nicely.  Serve with hot plain white rice.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>kuzhi paniyaram</ti>
<in>idli batter# 2 cups</in>
<in>onion# 1/2 cup</in>
<in>green chilly# 3-4</in>
<in>curry leaves# 1 string</in>
<in>black gram# 1 tsp</in>
<in>bengal gram# 1 tsp</in>
<in>mustard seeds# 1/2 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1. Add oil to a kadai and temper mustard seeds,chana dal,Urad dal.
2. Add the remaining ingredients except for the idly batter and sauté it .
3. Add the sautéed mixture to the batter.
4. Heat the kuzhi paniyaram griddle (puffed pancake griddle)
5. Pour the batter, let it cook for couple minutes and flip it ,so that it will cook on the other side.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>pepper chicken</ti>
<in>chicken# 2 lbs</in>
<in>garam masala</in>
<in>mustard seeds</in>
<in>jeera</in>
<in>curry leaves# 2 strands</in>
<in>onion# 2</in>
<in>green chilly# 2</in>
<in>chilly powder# 1 tsp</in>
<in>black pepper# 1 tsp</in>
<in>tomato# 2</in>
<in>coriander powder# 2 tsp</in>
<in>jeera# 1 tsp</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>garlic</in>
<in>salt# 2 tsp</in>
<in>coriander leaves</in>
<pr>
Preparation Steps:
1.Heat oil in a deep vessel.
2.Add the tempering mustard,cumin.
3.After it splutters add whole garam masala.
4.Add chopped onions and saute until golden brown.
5.Add salt, turmeric powder, ginger garlic paste,green chillies andcurry leaves.
6.Saute everything for 5 mins.
7.Add tomatoes and saute it until it becomes a gravy.
8.Add chilli powder,coriander  powder,cumin powder.
9.Saute everything for 10 mins in medium heat.
10.When oil comes out its the correct consistency
11.Now add chicken, little water and cover and cook.
12.After its cooked add the crushed pepper powder and check for seasoning.
13.To garnish add chopped corriander leaves. You can also add chunks of capsicum
</pr>
</recipe>
<recipe>
<ti>broccoli bajji</ti>
<in>gram flour#2 cups</in>
<in>rice flour#2 tsp</in>
<in>red chilly powder#2 tsp</in>
<in>baking soda#1 pinch</in>
<in>salt#to taste</in>
<in>broccoli#2 cups</in>
<in>water#1/2 cup</in>
<in>oil#1/4 cup</in>
<pr>
1. Mix thoroughly gram flour, rice flour, red chilly powder, baking soda and salt to make bajji flour.
2. Add water gradually to avoid lumps and make a smooth paste.
3. Heat oil in kadai. When the oil is hot enough, dump few broccoli florets in the bajji batter.
4. When the florets are completely coated with the batter, put the florets in the oil and deep fry.
5. Drain excess oil in a paper towel. Serve hot with tomato ketchup when the bajjis are crisp.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>mushroom cutlet</ti>
<in>mushroom#1 lb</in>
<in>potato#1</in>
<in>mixed vegetables#1 cup</in>
<in>onion#1/4</in>
<in>garlic#2 clove</in>
<in>green chilly#1</in>
<in>red chilly powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>garam masala powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>egg#2</in>
<in>bread#1 cup crumbs</in>
<in>coriander leaves#handful</in>
<in>salt#to taste</in>
<in>oil#1/4 cup</in>
<pr>
1. Cook the cubed potatoes and other vegetables until all the veggies are tender but firm. Drain excess water and keep aside. 
2. Heat a tsp of oil in a small pan and sauté the onions, green chilli and garlic until slightly browned. 
3. Switch off and add this to the veggies along with chopped mushrooms turmeric powder, red chilli powder, garam masala and salt.
4. Let this cool completely and then mash slightly along with egg whites to make a thick mixture. 
5. Take a small portion and roll them between your palms to make a ball, then press to flatten and shape as cutlet. 
6. Meanwhile spread a layer of bread crumbs on a plate for coating. Heat the oil in a pan for frying.
7. Now take each cutlet, place it on the bread crumbs to coat all sides. Drop that in the hot oil and fry until its golden on both sides. You can also pan fry the cutlets in a tawa. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>onion rings</ti>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>buttermilk#2/3 cup</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>maida#1 cup</in>
<in>salt#to taste</in>
<in>baking powder#1 tsp</in>
<pr>
1. Peel the onion, slice into 1/4 inch thick pieces and separate into rings. 
2. Soak the rings in buttermilk for 30 minutes.
3. Mix all the ingrediants under "batter" and keep it in a plate.
4. Heat oil in a deep pot for frying. 
5. Take few onion rings at a time from the buttermilk, coat it with the flour mixture and fry it.
6. Drain excess oil using a paper towel.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>crab cake</ti>
<in>crab meat#1 lb</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>potato#1</in>
<in>garlic#2 clove</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>egg#1</in>
<in>chilly powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>garam masala#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>bread#2 tsp crumbs</in>
<pr>
1. Boil the crab, remove the meat out and keep aside. You can get crab meat from the store.
2. Boil a potato and keep it aside.
3. Heat oil in a pan and saute the onions and garlic. 
4. Take mixing bowl, add the sauteed onions, garlic, boiled potato, shredded crab meat, cumin seeds and cilantro.
5. Add chilly powder, salt, garam masala and one egg. Mix everything together.
6. If the mixture is moist, add bread crumbs.
7. Make equal sized crab meat balls and then shape them as cutlets.
8. Fry them with few drops of oil on a hot griddle.
9. Serve as a snack or with fish biriyani.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>samosa</ti>
<in>tortilla#4</in>
<in>potato#2</in>
<in>carrot#1</in>
<in>green peas#1 cup</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>green chilly#2</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>ginger garlic paste#1 tsp</in>
<in>chilly powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>coriander powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder</in>
<in>cashew#6</in>
<in>lime#1/2</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Heat oil in a pan, fry the cumin seeds, ginger garlic paste, green chillies and cashew nuts.
2. Add the boiled potato pieces, boiled carrot pieces and green peas along with salt, chilly powder, corriander powder, turmeric powder and cilantro. 
3. Cook for 2 minutes for the flavours to blend together. Add few drops of lemon at the end. The filling is ready.
4. For the outer covering, cut a torilla in half.
5. Make a cone shape as shown in the picture. Stuff the filling inside.
6. Seal the edges using egg or with few drops of water.
7. Deep fry in oil till it becomes golden brown.
8. Drain excess oil using paper towel and serve hot with some ketchup or mint chutney.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>dahi vada</ti>
<in>urad dal#2 cups</in>
<in>green chilly#3</in>
<in>jeera powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>sugar#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>curd#2 cups</in>
<in>chilly powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<pr>
1.Soak Urad dal in water for an hour.
2.Grid The urad with the green chillies and salt, without adding water.
3.In a kadai add oil let it heat upto 350 degrees.(Drop a small piece of batter to see if the oil is warm enough).
3. Make patties of urad dal and add it to oil and fry it.
4.When the vadas turn golden brown scoop it out from the oil and drop it in a bowl of salt water ,let it soak for few minutes,meanwhile make one more batch of vada.
5.Let the vada soak in water until the second batch is done and repeat the same for the second batch.
6.Beat the yogurt in a bowl with little salt and sugar(optional), jeera powder .
7.Squeeze the vada(s)from the water and put it in the yogurt mixture,let it soak for a while sprinkle it with little chilli powder.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>corn vada</ti>
<in>corn#1 cup</in>
<in>chana dal#1 cup</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>chilly#6</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>asafoetida</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Soak the chana dal for atleast an hour. Drain and coarsely grind it .
2. To this add the corn, onion, red chillies, ginger, cumin seeds, turmeric, curry leaves, asafoetida and salt.
3. Make balls out of the above mixture, shape them as vadas or cutlets. 
4. Grease a baking tray and line the vadas. Sprinkle 1 or 2 drops of oil on top of each vada.
5. Bake it in an oven preheated to 350 degrees for 45 minutes to 1 hour. 
6. Serve hot with mint chutney or eat as such.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>sprout salad</ti>
<in>sprouts#1 cup</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>tomato#1</in>
<in>green chilly#1</in>
<in>lemon#1/2</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>mint leaves#3</in>
<pr>
1. Mix the onions, tomato,green chilly, sprouts, chopped mint and cilantro.
2. Add few drops of lemon juice to it with little salt. 
3. Mix everything nicely and serve as a healthy snack.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>momos</ti>
<in>maida#2 cups</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>meat#1 lb</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>garlic#8 clove</in>
<in>soy sauce#2 tsp</in>
<in>chilly sauce#1 tsp</in>
<in>pepper powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
For the filling
(You could just mix all the ingredients under 'for filling' and use it but I prefer to cook it before stuffing.)
1.Heat oil in a pan and fry the onions and garlic till it is translicent.
2. Add the ground meat and fry till the meat becomes nice and brown.
3. Add all the sauces, pepper powder and salt and mix well. The stuffing is ready.
 
For the wrapper
1. Mix the flour, salt and knead it adding little water at a time to form a stiff dough.
2. Divide the dough into lemon sized balls.
3. Roll out the balls into thin chappatti.
4. Using a small bottle cap or a cookie cutter, cut out small circles (about 3-4" diameter) of the rolled out dough.
5. Keep these wrappers ready to make the momos.
 
Making Momos
1. Take a rolled and cut out wrapper and apply a little bit of water on the edges.
2. Put a tblsp of the filling in the center.
3. Fold the wrapper over the filling and seal the edges forming a half moon shape. You could also make other shapes.
4. Place the momos on any steaming dish (like vegetable steamer, idli plates, dhokla stand)
5. Steam on medium flame for 15 minutes.
6. Serve hot with some spicy chutney, sauce or pickle.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>ragi vada</ti>
<in>ragi flour#2 cups</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>spinach#1 cup</in>
<in>chilly powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1.In a bowl, add Ragi flour, Spinach, onion, Chilly powder, Salt, curry leaves , Cilantro and mix well.
2.Add required water and make a soft dough ( like chapathi dough).
3.Heat Oil in a pan. Take a small amount of dough, press it with the help of fingers and drop it in hot Oil.
4. Fry till it turns into crispy or till the bubbles are almost stopped. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>pakoda</ti>
<in>gram flour</in>
<in>vegetables</in>
<in>red chilly powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>cumin powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>baking soda#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
Method
1. Cut the vegetables into small pieces. Generally raw banana, potato, brinjal and onion are made into thin slices, cauliflower is cut into bite sized florets, bread is cut diagonally to form a triangle.
2. Mix all the dry ingredients (besan, corn flour, red chilli powder, baking soda, cumin powder, turmeric powder and salt) in a bowl.
2. Add water little by little while mixing it constantly to make a smooth batter.
3. In the mean time heat oil for deep frying.
4. Dip the vegetables/bread/shrimp/chicken one at a time in the batter so that it is completely coated with the batter and drop in hot oil.
5. Do not overcrowd the oil. There should be enough space for the bajjis to float in the oil without getting stuck to each other. Deep fry till it becomes golden brown. 
6. Drain excess oil in paper towels and serve hot with some chutney, hot sauce or ketchup.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>onion vada</ti>
<in>onion#2</in>
<in>gram flour#3/2 cups</in>
<in>rice flour#1/2 cup</in>
<in>green chilly#3</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>cashew</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>asafoetida</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1. Heat the oil in a kadai for deep frying.
2. Make thin slices of the onions and sprinkle some salt on it.
3. Add the chopped curry leaves, cumin seeds and cashews.
4. Add asafoetida, chilly powder (or green chillies), rice flour and the gram flour to this.
5. Add 1 or 2 tblsp of the hot oil along with this and mix everything together.
6. The salt draws out the moisture from the onions. If neededJust sprinkle few drops of water and make a dough.
7. Pinch a small portion of the dough and drop it in the medium hot oil.
8. Fry till golden brown.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>unniappam</ti>
<in>rice flour#1 cup</in>
<in>wheat flour#2 tsp</in>
<in>banana#2</in>
<in>brown sugar#1/2 cup</in>
<in>cardamom powder#3/4 tsp</in>
<in>baking powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>sesame seeds#2 tsp</in>
<pr>
1. Blend the banana nicely using a blender or mixie.
2. Add rice flour , brown sugar, baking powder, cardomom and blend it together. Add the sesame seeds to batter.
3. The consistency of the batter should be little thicker than the idli batter.
4. Heat the paniyaram griddle(puffed pancake griddle-made of cast Iron).
5. Add few drops of oil to each hole and pour the batter.
6. When the edges turns golden brown flip it,so that the other side will cook.
7. Allow it to cook on medium heat for another couple of minutes. If the heat is too high, the outside will get browned up too fast before the inside is cooked.
8. When the unniappam is done, it is like a ball and comes out easily from the griddle. Yummy unniappam is ready to serve. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>fish cutlet</ti>
<in>fish#4 fillets</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>garlic#3 clove</in>
<in>ginger#1 slice</in>
<in>egg#2</in>
<in>garam masala#1 tsp</in>
<in>chilly powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>cumin powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>bread#1/2 cup crumbs</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1. Take water in a pan and bring it to a boil. Add the fish fillets to the water and let it cook nicely (till the fish turns opaque).
2. Remove the fish from the water and shred it into small pieces.
3. Heat oil in a small skillet and saute the onions, ginger and garlic in it till the raw smell vanishes.
4. Add the shredded fish to it along with garam masala, salt, chilly powder , cumin powder and cilantro.
5. Keep stirring the mixture until it becomes very dry. This is essential for the cutlets to bind together very well.
6. Once the above mixture is cool enough to handle, add one raw egg to it. Mix everything nicely with hands.
(The egg is mainly used for binding. You can also use a handful of cooked rice or a boiled and mashed potato instead.)  
7. Beat another egg in a bowl.
8. Make small round balls out of the cutlet mixture and shape it into patties. You can make any shape - round, oval, heart shape, cylindrical etc.
9. Dip the patties in the beaten egg then coat it with bread crumbs. Now you can deep fry, shallow fry or bake these cutlets.
10. Serve hot with ketchup or hot sauce.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>medhu vada</ti>
<in>black gram#1 cup</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>green chilly</in>
<in>black pepper#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>asafoetida</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Soak the urad dal overnight or a minimum of 1/2 an hour.
2. Drain the water and grind the dal in grinder/blender/mixie using as little water as possible.

3. Take this urad dal batter in a bowl and add required salt, grated ginger, green/red chillies, crushed pepper, asafoetida and chopped curry leaves.
4. You could add in the optional ingredients too if you prefer. Mix the batter nicely.
5. In the meantime, heat the oil for frying the vadas.
6. To shape the vadas, wet your hand, take a small portion of batter on the palm your hand.
7. Using the finger of your other hand or the thumb of the same hand, make a small hole in the center of the batter.
8. Gently slide the batter into the hot oil. The hole helps in even cooking of the vadas inside and out. The vadas should be fried in medium heat.
9. Once the vadas get golden brown on one side, flip it and cook the other side.
10. Once the vada fully turns golden brown, remove it and let it rest on paper towels to remove excess oil.
11. Serve hot with coconut chutney or sambar all by itself or with any south indian breakfast items like idli, pongal etc.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>masala vada</ti>
<in>bengal gram#2 cups</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>dry red chilly#4</in>
<in>fennel seeds#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>asafoetida</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1. Wash and soak the bengal gram in water for atleast half an hour. It is better if you are able to soak for an hour or 2.
2. Drain the water completely. Take the soaked dal, garlic, ginger, dry red chillies, curry leaves, salt and fennel seeds in a blender/ mixie. 
3. Pulse it a few times till the mixture is partially ground. We need some texture in the batter. Do not add any water. The dal must have absorbed enough water for grinding.
4. Heat oil for deep frying in a frying pan/ kadai.
5. Mix the chopped onions (if needed) with the vada batter.
6. Take a small ball of the batter and flatten it between your palm. 
7. Drop the flattened vada into the hot oil and fry till it becomes golden brown.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>badam pakoda</ti>
<in>almond#1 cup</in>
<in>rice flour#4 tsp</in>
<in>gram flour#4 tsp</in>
<in>onion#4 tsp</in>
<in>coriander leaves#4 tsp</in>
<in>bread#4 slices</in>
<in>black pepper powder</in>
<in>chilly powder</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1. Soak the almonds for 3-4 hours in water. 
2. Remove the skin and grate the same in cheese grater.
3. Remove the border of the bread and crush the bread.
4. Mix all the ingredients to form a dough.  If need be, sprinkle little water.
5. When you take the same in your hand to make round/elongated shape, the same should be binding.
6. When the desired shape is made, deep fry them and serve hot with chutney/sauce.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>bread pakoda</ti>
<in>gram flour#2 cups</in>
<in>chilly powder#2 tsp</in>
<in>ajwain#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>turmeric powder</in>
<in>rice flour#2 tsp</in>
<in>bread#6 slices</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1. In a bowl, mix the besan, chilli powder, ajwain, hing powder, rice flour, salt. 
2. Add water and make a smooth batter for the bhaji (pakoda).  
3. Heat two tsp oil and mix with the batter for a crispy pakoda. If you add the hot oil in the mix, there is no need to add soda.
4. Cut the bread slices into four pieces. 
5. Dip each piece in the batter and deep fry.  
6. Remove the excess oil by placing them in paper napkin. Serve hot with sauce/chutney. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>lentil soup</ti>
<in>masoor dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>olive oil#1 tsp</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>garlic#2 clove</in>
<in>green chilly#1</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>coriander seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>peppercorns#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>lemon</in>
<pr>
1. Dry roast the cumin seeds, corriander seeds and peppercons. Then crush it corsely using a pestle/blender.
2.Heat oil in a saucepan and sauté the onions, garlic and green chilly over medium heat for 10 minutes.
3. Add remaining ingredients, except lemon juice, and bring to boil. Cover and cook over medium heat for 25 minutes until the lentils are cooked.
4. Puree with hand blender(perferable) or in a blender.
5. Return the pureed mixture back to saucepan and reheat.(If needed add hot water to dilute a little). 
6. Stir in lemon juice and serve hot. Try this hearty and healthy soup on a cold winter day or while having a sore throat.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>capsicum soup</ti>
<in>capsicum#1</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>garlic##2 clove</in>
<in>tomato#1/2</in>
<in>green chilly#2</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>pepper</in>
<in>cumin powder#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>olive oil#2 tsp</in>
<pr>
1. Heat Oil in a pan, saute the garlic and onion for a minute.
2. Add the capsicum (bell pepper), tomato, green chillies and Cilantro and cook till the capsicum becomes soft. Switch off.
3. Puree the mixture using a hand blender or a mixie. Strain the pureed mixture to remove the seeds and skin. (Some people like to continue without straining but the texture will be different. This step is a must to get a smooth and creamy soup.)
4. Add this strained soup back to the pot and add the chicken/ vegetable stock to it. Switch on the stove.
5. Add required salt, cumin powder and required pepper powder. Bring the soup to a boil.
6. Add the cream to the soup to thicken it. Alternatively, mix little corn flour with some water and add to the soup while boiling.
7. Simmer for another 5 -10 minutes and switch off.
8. Garnish with heavy cream, crutons, toasted bread piece, fresh herbs etc according to your taste and imagination. Serve hot.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>spinach soup</ti>
<in>spinach#3 cups</in>
<in>ginger#1 tsp</in>
<in>garlic#4 clove</in>
<in>bay leaf#1</in>
<in>milk#1 cup</in>
<in>pepper powder#1 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Boil spinach in water for 5-7 minutes with bay leaf (tejpatta), ginger and garlic (I tried it in micro for 5 mins and it retains the nice green color of the spinach).
2. After letting it cool, blend it all and then strain it.
3. Add seasoning/broth, salt, pepper to the spinach puree and let it boil for 3-4 minutes.
4. Add milk mixed with corn starch. Keep stirring until it boils.
5. Serve hot with garnishing of your choice. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>pumpkin soup</ti>
<in>red pumpkin#1/4 kg</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>clove#3</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>coconut</in>
<in>butter#2 tsp</in>
<pr>
 1. Wash and remove the skin of pumpkin and slice it.
2. Peel the oninon and slice it
3. Add butter in a kadai, add the clove, saute for a minute.
4. Add onionS and saute till it changes the colour little bit
5. Add pumpkin slices and saute the same with little salt till soft.
6. Allow to cool. Grind it in mixer with 1 cup of water. 
7. Transfer it into a kadai and boil the same. Check the salt,if required add more.
8. Add black salt, roasted cumin powder and the coconut milk.
9. Mix well and remove from the gas. Do not boil after adding coconut milk. Consistency should not be watery.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>avocado milkshake</ti>
<in>avocado#1</in>
<in>milk#2 cups</in>
<in>sugar#4 tsp</in>
<in>ice</in>
<pr>
1.Using a sharp knife cut lengthwise around the avocado. Follow the contour of the avocado by letting the knife blade touching the large pit to get 2 halves.
2. Pull the two lengthwise pieces apart gently.
3. Using a knife, remove the pit. Use a spoon to scoop out the flesh.
4. Add the flesh along with milk, sugar and ice cubes.
5. Blend everything well to get a creamy milkshake. Serve as a yummy yummy refreshing drink. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>mango lassi</ti>
<in>mango#1</in>
<in>yogurt#1/2 cup</in>
<in>ice#1/2 cup</in>
<pr>
1. Blend the yogurt in the mixie/ blender first.
2. Add the mango pieces and ice cubes and blend till a everything is blended nicely.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>strawberry lassi</ti>
<in>strawberry#10</in>
<in>sugar#3 tsp</in>
<in>milk#1/2 cup</in>
<in>ice#5 cubes</in>
<in>yogurt#3 tsp</in>
<pr>
1.Wash the Strawberries and cut off the leaves .
2.Blend Stawberries with sugar first.
3.Blend again smoothly with the remaining ingredients
4.Serve cold and add sugar according to taste 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>sweet lassi</ti>
<in>yogurt#1 cup</in>
<in>sugar</in>
<in>rose water#1 tsp</in>
<in>cardamom powder</in>
<pr>
1. Blend together all the above ingredients together using a hand mixer or a mixie until it becomes frothy.
2. Garnish with fresh mint leaves, pistachios and serve as a cool, healthy and refreshing drink. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>cherry lassi</ti>
<in>yogurt#1 cup</in>
<in>milk#1/2 cup</in>
<in>cherry#1 cup</in>
<in>sugar#3 tsp</in>
<pr>
1. Blend together the cherries, yogurt, water/milk and sugar in a blender till it becomes frothy.
2. Pour into individual glasses and garnish with some fresh cherries.
3. Chill and serve. This can be refrigerated for up to 24 hours.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>chocolate grape shake</ti>
<in>chocolate#15 chips</in>
<in>grapes#25</in>
<in>sugar#1 tsp</in>
<in>milk#1/2 cup</in>
<pr>
1. Blend the grapes with chocolate chips and a little water in the mixie.
2. Then add the milk,sugar and blend well.
3. Filter the contents.
4. Serve it cold 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>milkshake</ti>
<in>fruit#1 cup</in>
<in>milk#3/4 cup</in>
<in>sugar#1 tsp</in>
<in>ice#1/4 cup</in>
<in>vanilla#2 tsp</in>
<pr>
1.Clean and peel the fruit that you use and cut into small chunks. Be careful to remove any seeds if present. You can also use store bought fruit puree.
2.Blend the fruit chunks/puree with all the other ingredients until it is smooth and creamy.
3.Pour in a tall glass, top with some whipped cream and serve cold.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>ginger cardamom tea</ti>
<in>milk#1 cup</in>
<in>tea#2 tsp</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>cardamom</in>
<in>sugar</in>
<in>lemon#1/2</in>
<pr>
1. In a saucepan, bring water to a boil along with crushed ginger and cardamon pods.
(You could also add ginger powder and cardamom powder)
2. Add the tea leaves and let it come to a rolling boil again.
3. Reduce the flame and let it simmer for 3-4 minutes for all the essence of the tea to be released in the water.
4. The basic ginger cardamom tea is ready. You could flavour it in different ways. I've given 2 options below.
 
Type - I (Ginger tea with milk - Chai)
5. Add the milk to the above tea water and bring it to a boil.
6. Strain the tea using a strainer, add enough sugar and enjoy it piping hot with biscuits.

Type II (Ginger Lemon tea with honey)     
5. Strain the tea to a cup and squeeze in the lemon juice.
6. Add honey to taste and enjoy it after a heavy meal or as a refreshing drink. This type of tea could be served hot or cold.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>spicy lassi</ti>
<in>curd#1 cup</in>
<in>green chilly#3</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<pr>
1. Crush the green chillies, ginger and cilantro using a mortar and pestle or using the pulse mode of the mixie.
2. Beat the curd nicely using a fork and add the water to it. 
3. Mix the curd-water mixture nicely using a hand blender or with a spoon.
4. Add the crushed mixture, torn curry leaves and required salt and mix everything together.
5. Serve on a hot summer day as a refreshing drink or have with some plain rice.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>raspberry tea</ti>
<in>raspberry#1 cup</in>
<in>tea#3/4 tsp</in>
<in>sugar#2 tsp</in>
<in>ice</in>
<pr>
1. Bring the water to a boil and switch off.
2. Add the tea and raspberries to the boiling water. Cover and let it stand for 5 minutes.
3. Strain the tea into serving glasses.
4. Add ice cubes and sugar. Mix well.
5. Garnish with some raspberries and serve chilled.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>raspberry lassi</ti>
<in>raspberry#1 cup</in>
<in>yogurt#1/2 cup</in>
<in>sugar#3 tsp</in>
<in>mint leaves#3</in>
<in>black pepper</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Blend all the above ingredients in a blender until it becomes creamy and frothy.
2. Garnish with fresh mint leaves, fresh raspberries.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>herbal juice</ti>
<in>tulasi leaves#1 tsp</in>
<in>mint leaves#1 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>jaggery#2 tsp</in>
<in>honey#1 tsp</in>
<in>curd#1/2 cup</in>
<in>lemon</in>
<pr>
1. Add all the ingredients one by one by adding 150 ml water.
2. You can add more sugar before serving. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>beetroot milkshake</ti>
<in>beetroot#1</in>
<in>milk#300 ml</in>
<in>sugar#4 tsp</in>
<in>cardamom powder</in>
<in>whipped cream</in>
<in>ice</in>
<in>basil seeds#1 tsp</in>
<pr>
1. Cook the grated beetroot with 2 cups of water.  
2. When it is tender, remove from gas and allow to cool.
3. Blend the same in a mixer/blender nicely.  
4. Add the milk, sugar, cardomom powder, whip cream and blend again. 
5. Serve chilled  with or without ice cream by adding subja.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>mango lassi</ti>
<in>mango#1</in>
<in>yogurt#4 tsp</in>
<in>whipped cream#2 tsp</in>
<in>sugar#4 tsp</in>
<in>saffron</in>
<in>ice</in>
<pr>
Mix all the ingredients in a blender and blend it. Serve chilled.  
If you are using crushed ice, serve immediately.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>mango milkshake</ti>
<in>mango#2</in>
<in>milk#1 cup</in>
<in>cardamom powder</in>
<in>sugar#3 tsp</in>
<in>ice</in>
<pr>
1. Wash, peel the mango and cut it into cubes.
2. Take the mango cubes, milk, sugar, cardamom powder and ice cubes in a blender.
3. Make a smooth puree. Pour into glasses. 
4. Garnish with a drizzle of mango pulp or fresh milk on top. This forms a nice pattern. Serve immediately.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>cucumber juice</ti>
<in>cucumber#1</in>
<in>lemon#1/2</in>
<in>sugar#4 tsp</in>
<in>ice</in>
<pr>
1. Peel the cucumber, wash it and cut it into big cubes.
2. Take these cubes in a blender along with the cold water, lemon juice and sugar.
4. Blend it to a smooth paste. Sieve it. 
5. Add some ice cubes and garnish with a lemon slice and a mint leaf. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>idli</ti>
<in>idli rice</in>
<in>black gram</in>
<in>fenugreek seeds</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Soak rice and black gram separately in water for atleast 1 hour. Soaking overnight can be done too. Add fenugreek seeds to black gram.
2. Drain the water and grind the black gram to a silky soft texture.
3. Next grind the rice coarsely. Mix it with black gram batter along with salt.
4. Now leave the batter to rest and ferment for atleast 6 hours till the batter rises to almost double the size.
5. Grease the idli plates with few drops of oil and fill with idli batter.
6. Steam them for about 10 minutes till they rise and become firm. (If you do not have idli stand, grease stainless steel tumblers,  fill it with batter and steam it as shown in the picture.)
7. Switch off the stove and let it rest for a minute or 2. After that use a wet spoon to remove the idlis from the idli plate.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>rava idli</ti>
<in>rava#2 cups</in>
<in>green chilly#2</in>
<in>curd#2 cups</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>oil#2 tsp</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>baking soda</in>
<in>urad dal</in>
<in>bengal gram</in>
<in>mustard seeds</in>
<in>cashew</in>
<in>ghee</in>
<pr>
1. Roast the rava and cashews in the ghee. Mix it with sour curd and keep aside for 10-15 minutes.
2. Heat oil in a small pan, temper mustard seeds, chopped curry leaves, urad dal and bengal gram dal.
3. Once the dals are nicely cooked add the onions and green chillies and saute for 2 minutes.
4. Pour this over the rava-curd mixture.
5. Add cooking soda, salt and chopped cilantro to the above mixture and mix everything well. Add little water if the batter is too thick.
6. Grease the idli plates with few drops of oil and pour the batter.
7. Steam it for 15 minutes like idlis. Serve with spicy pudhina chutney and/or sambhar.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>banana idli</ti>
<in>rava#1 cup</in>
<in>coconut#1/4 cup</in>
<in>banana#4</in>
<in>jaggery</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>baking soda#1/2 tsp</in>
<in>ghee</in>
<pr>
1. Mash the bananas, preferably by hand.
2. Add all the other ingredients and mix well.
3. Add little water and make it like idli batter.
4. Grease the idli plates with some ghee and pour a spoonful of batter in it.
5. Steam for 15 minutes.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>dosa</ti>
<in>rice#3.5 cups</in>
<in>urad dal#1 cup</in>
<in>fenugreek seeds#2 tsp</in>
<in>bengal gram#2 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Wash and soak the rice and urad dal with bengalgram dal and fenugreek seeds separately or together . Traditionally it used to soaked separately and ground separately. But with modern mixies and grinders you can grind everything together itself.
2. Similarly overnight soaking is good. But for urgent situations, even 1 hour of soaking will do for modern mixies and grinders.
3. After soaking, drain and grind it to a smooth paste with salt and water enough to make a batter little thinner than idli batter. If the batter becomes thicker you can always add water later. 
4. Let this batter ferment overnight till it raises to double its size.
5. Grease a non stick dosa pan and pour a spoonful of batter. Spread it using the back of the spoon using circular motion to about 9 inch round dosa.
6. Add few drops of oil on top. 
7. Once it turns slightly brown, flip and brown the other side too.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>ragi dosa</ti>
<in>ragi flour#2 cups</in>
<in>urad dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>salt#1 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1. Soak urad dal and ragi grains separately for minimum 3 hours or overnight.
2. Grind the urad dal separately till it become fluffy. 
3. Next grind the ragi seperately (if using ragi grains).
4. Mix the urad dal batter and ragi batter together with required salt.
5. Whichever method you follow, let the batter ferment overnight or until it doubles in volume.
6. After it ferments, you can make idlis or dosa immediately. You can also store the batter in the fridge for 3-4 days.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>dal dosa</ti>
<in>rice#1 cup</in>
<in>masoor dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>chana dal#2 tsp</in>
<in>dry red chilly#3</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>asafoetida</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Wash and soak the rice and dal for atleast 1 hour.
2. After soaking, drain and grind it to a smooth paste with asafoetida, dry red chillies, ginger, salt and water enough to make a dosa batter.
3.  If the batter becomes thicker you can always add water later. (You can grind the carrot along with the batter or add grated carrot to the batter.)
4. The batter will be a beautiful orange colour. Let this batter rest for atleast 1/2 an hour. 
5. Grease a non stick dosa pan and pour a spoonful of batter. Spread it using the back 
of the spoon using circular motion to about 9 inch round dosa.
6. Add few drops of oil on top.  Once it turns slightly brown, flip and brown the other side too.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>banana dosa</ti>
<in>banana#2</in>
<in>rice flour#1/4 cup</in>
<in>maida#2 tsp</in>
<in>cardamom powder</in>
<in>sugar</in>
<in>raisins#2 tsp</in>
<in>cashew#2 tsp</in>
<in>ghee</in>
<pr>
1. Mash the bananas nicely with a masher or with hands.
2. Add rice flour, maida, sugar and cardomon powder. 
3. Mix everything together to get a thick batter. You can mix with your hands or use a blender.
4. Mix the raisins  and cashews with the batter.
5. Heat a griddle and pour a spoonful of batter and spread gently. It will be thicker than normal dosa.
6. Pour few drops of ghee on top. Fry on medium flame till the dosa is completely cooked and golden brown on both sides.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>rava dosa</ti>
<in>rava#1 cup</in>
<in>rice flour#1/2 cup</in>
<in>maida#2 tsp</in>
<in>yogurt#1 cup</in>
<in>onion#1</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>peppercorns#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly#1</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>cilantro</in>
<in>curry leaves</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1. Mix the rava, rice flour, maida and required salt.
2. Add finely chopped onions, green chilly, cilantro, curry leaves, grated ginger, cumin seeds and crushed peppercorns to that.
3. Add the yogurt/buttermilk and required water to make a batter thinner than normal dosa batter. Let the batter rest for 10-15 minutes.
4. Heat a non stick dosa pan on medium high heat. 
5. Take a spoon ful of batter and spread the batter from the outer side of the pan. (unlike the normal dosa which you spread from the inside out.)
6. Pour few drops of oil on top and let it cook for a couple of minutes on one side. 
7. Gently flip the dosa and cook until both the sides are golden brown.
8. Serve with coconut chutney and sambhar. You can also stuff it with masala and make rava masala dosa.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>adai aviyal</ti>
<in>rice#1 cup</in>
<in>toor dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>chana dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>urad dal#2 tsp</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>dry red chilly#4</in>
<in>asafoetida#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1.Wash and soak the rice and lentils for 1 hour.
2.Grind them together to a coarse texture along with dry red chillies, ginger, cumin seeds, asafoetida, salt and required water.
3.You could make the batter as thick or thin as you want. Do not make it very runny.
4.To the batter add your choice of ingredients under "additional ingredients" and mix together.
5.Take a spoonfull of the batter and pour on a dosa kal or griddle.
6.Spread the batter using circular motion with the back of the spoon.
7.Pour some oil in the center of the adai and also in the sides.
8.Cook until both the sides are done. Usually takes 2 minutes on each side. Leave the adai little longer on the tava if you prefer crispy adais.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>vegetable adai</ti>
<in>rice#1 cup</in>
<in>toor dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>chana dal#1/2 cup</in>
<in>urad dal#2 tsp</in>
<in>vegetables#1 cup</in>
<in>salt</in>
<in>dry red chilly#4</in>
<in>asafoetida#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>cumin seeds#1 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<pr>
1.Wash and soak the rice and lentils for 1 hour.
2.Grind them together to a coarse texture along with the vegetable you plan to use, dry red chillies, ginger, cumin seeds, asafoetida, salt and the required water.
3.Make the batter in the consistency of a normal dosa batter. The batter can be used immediately to make dosas and does not need to be fermented.
4. Heat a dosa tawa or non stick pan or a griddle on medium high heat. It should be hot enough so that when you sprinkle few drops of water, it should sizzle away.
5.Take a spoonfull of the batter and pour in the center.
6.Spread the batter using clockwise circular motion with the back of the spoon.
7.Pour some oil in the center of the dosai and also on the sides.
8.Cook until both the sides are done. Usually it takes 2 minutes on each side. Leave it a little longer on the tawa if you want it crispy. 
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>green dosa</ti>
<in>green gram#2 cups</in>
<in>rice#4 tsp</in>
<in>green chilly#6</in>
<in>ginger</in>
<in>cumin seeds#2 tsp</in>
<in>oil</in>
<in>salt</in>
<pr>
1. Soak the green gram and rice for atleast 1 hour and drain the water. Longer soaking would be good.
2. Add this soaked lentil and rice to a mixie/blender along with the ginger piece and green chillies.
3. Add enough water and required salt and grind to a smooth paste.
4. Remove the batter and mix the cumin seeds with it.
5. Heat a griddle/ dosa pan. Check if it is hot enough by sprinkling few drops of water. The water will sizzle right away.
6. Pour a laddlefull of batter in the center and spread it into a nice round shape using the back of the spoon.
7. Sprinkle few chopped onions and few drops of oil on top.
8. After it turns golden brown at the bottom, flip it over.
9. After it gets cooked on both sides, remove from the griddle.
</pr>
</recipe>

<recipe>
<ti>instant rice flour dosa</ti>
<in>rice flour#1 cup</in>
<in>egg#2</in>
<in>green chilly#3</in>
<in>onion#1/2</in>
<in>turmeric powder</in>
<in>chilly powder#1/4 tsp</in>
<in>ginger garlic paste#1/4 tsp</in>
<pr>
1. Mix all the ingredients in a bowl and add enough water. 
2. The batter should not be too thick or too thin. It should be of medium consistency. 
3. Grind the cumin seeds and coconut and mix them with the batter as well. Keep it for 10 minutes. 
4. After 10 minutes, pour them in a dosa pan and make yummy masala dosas. 
</pr>
</recipe>
</recipes>